<control ref='D2.3' name='Ensure Docker is allowed to make changes to iptables' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Iptables are used to set up, maintain, and inspect the tables of IP packet filter rules in the
                        Linux kernel. Allow the Docker daemon to make changes to the iptables.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Rationale:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Docker will never make changes to your system iptables rules if you choose to set it so. Docker
                        server would automatically make the needed changes to iptables based on how you choose your
                        networking options for the containers if it is allowed to do so. It is recommended to let Docker
                        server make changes to iptables automatically to avoid networking misconfiguration that might
                        hamper the communication between containers and to the outside world. Additionally, it would
                        save you the hassle of updating iptables every time you choose to run the containers or modify
                        networking options.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Do not run the Docker daemon with --iptables=false parameter. For example, do not start the
                        Docker daemon as below:&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        dockerd --iptables=false&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Impact:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Docker daemon service start requires iptables rules to be enabled before it starts. Any restarts
                        of iptables during docker daemon operation may result in losing docker-created rules. Adding
                        iptables-persistent to your iptables install can assist with mitigating this impact.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Docker and Iptables' url='https://fralef.me/docker-and-iptables.html' />
            <reference name='Docker docs: Container communication' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/userguide/networking/default_network/container-communication/' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='2.3' supportedStandardRef='Level 1 - Docker' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;blockquote&gt;
                            ps -ef | grep dockerd&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            Ensure that the --iptables parameter is either not present or not set to false.
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>