<control ref='D2.11' name='Ensure that authorization for Docker client commands are enabled' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Use native Docker authorization plugins or a third party authorization mechanism with Docker
                        daemon to manage access to Docker client commands.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Rationale:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Docker's out-of-the-box authorization model is all or nothing. Any user with
                        permission to access the Docker daemon can run any Docker client command. The same is true for callers using
                        Docker's remote API to contact the daemon. If you require greater access
                        control, you can create authorization plugins and add them to your Docker daemon configuration. Using an authorization
                        plugin, a Docker administrator can configure granular access policies for managing access to
                        Docker daemon. Third party integrations of Docker may implement their own authorization models
                        to require authorization with the Docker daemon outside of docker's native authorization plugin
                        (i.e. Kubernetes, Cloud Foundry, Openshift).&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Step 1: Install/Create an authorization plugin.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Step 2: Configure the authorization policy as desired.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Step 3: Start the docker daemon as below: dockerd --authorization-plugin=&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Impact:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Each docker command specifically passes through an authorization plugin mechanism. This might
                        introduce a slight performance drop. Third party use of alternative container engines that
                        utilize the docker daemon may provide alternative mechanisms to provide this security control.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Docker docs: Authorization access' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/commandline/dockerd/#access-authorization' />
            <reference name='Docker docs: Authorization plugins' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/extend/plugins_authorization/' />
            <reference name='Docker github: Authorization twistlock' url='https://github.com/twistlock/authz' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='2.11' supportedStandardRef='Level 2 - Docker' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;blockquote&gt;
                            ps -ef | grep dockerd&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            Ensure that the --authorization-plugin parameter is set as appropriate if using docker
                            native authorization.&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            docker search hello-world&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            Ensure that docker daemon requires authorization to perform the above command.
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>