<control ref='D2.16' name='Ensure daemon-wide custom seccomp profile is applied, if needed' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>You can choose to apply your custom seccomp profile at the daemon-wide level if needed and
                        override Docker's default seccomp profile.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Rationale:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        A large number of system calls are exposed to every userland process with many of them going
                        unused for the entire lifetime of the process. Most of the applications do not need all the
                        system calls and thus benefit by having a reduced set of available system calls. The reduced set
                        of system calls reduces the total kernel surface exposed to the application and thus improves
                        application security. You could apply your own custom seccomp profile instead of Docker's
                        default seccomp profile. Alternatively, if Docker's default profile is good for your
                        environment, you can choose to ignore this recommendation.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        By default, Docker's default seccomp profile is applied. If this is good for your environment,
                        no action is necessary. Alternatively, if you choose to apply your own seccomp profile, use the
                        --seccomp-profile flag at daemon start or put it in the daemon runtime parameters file.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        dockerd --seccomp-profile&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Impact:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        A misconfigured seccomp profile could possibly interrupt your container environment.
                        Docker-default blocked calls have been carefully scrutinized. These address some critical
                        vulnerabilities/issues within container environments (for example, kernel key ring calls). So,
                        you should be very careful while overriding the defaults.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Docker docs: Seccomp' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/security/seccomp/' />
            <reference name='Docker github: docker 26276' url='https://github.com/docker/docker/pull/26276' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='2.16' supportedStandardRef='Level 2 - Docker' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>Run the below command and review the seccomp profile listed in the Security Options
                            section. If it is default, that means, Docker's default seccomp profile is applied.&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            docker info --format '{{ .SecurityOptions }}'
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>