<control ref="RESTRICT-HTTP-METHODS" name="Ensure that the application accepts only a defined set of required HTTP request methods" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="admin" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        HTTP offers a number of methods that can be used to perform actions on the web server. Many of
                        theses methods are designed to aid developers in deploying and testing HTTP applications. These
                        HTTP methods can be used for nefarious purposes if the web server is misconfigured.
                        Additionally, Cross Site Tracing (XST), a form of cross site scripting using the server's HTTP
                        TRACE method, is examined.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        While GET and POST are by far the most common methods that are used to access information
                        provided by a web server, the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) allows several other (and
                        somewhat less known) methods. RFC 2616 (which describes HTTP version 1.1 which is the standard
                        today) defines the following eight methods:
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;HEAD&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;GET&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;POST&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;PUT&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;DELETE&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;TRACE&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;OPTIONS&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;CONNECT&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Some of these methods can potentially pose a security risk for a web application, as they allow
                        an attacker to modify the files stored on the web server and, in some scenarios, steal the
                        credentials of legitimate users. More specifically, the methods that should be disabled are the
                        following:
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;PUT: &lt;/b&gt;This method allows a client to upload new files on the web
                        server. An attacker can exploit it by uploading malicious files (e.g.: an asp file that executes
                        commands by invoking cmd.exe), or by simply using the victim's server as a file repository.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DELETE:&lt;/b&gt; This method allows a client to delete a file on the web
                        server. An attacker can exploit it as a very simple and direct way to deface a web site or to
                        mount a DoS attack.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;CONNECT: &lt;/b&gt;This method could allow a client to use the web server as
                        a proxy.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;TRACE: &lt;/b&gt;This method simply echoes back to the client whatever string
                        has been sent to the server, and is used mainly for debugging purposes. This method, originally
                        assumed harmless, can be used to mount an attack known as Cross Site Tracing, which has been
                        discovered by Jeremiah Grossman (see links at the bottom of the page).&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        If an application needs one or more of these methods, such as REST Web Services (which may
                        require PUT or DELETE), it is important to check that their usage is properly limited to trusted
                        users and safe conditions.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Ensure that the application accepts only the HTTP requests GET and POST. The HTTP requests
                        TRACE, PUT and DELETE are blocked.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references>
                        <reference name="OWASP test HTTP methods" url="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Test_HTTP_Methods_(OTG-CONFIG-006)"/>
                    </references>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="CM-2" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="CM-6" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="11.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-1"/>
                        <standard ref="11.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="11.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="A7:2017-Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                        <standard ref="A5:2017-Broken Access Control" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check that the application only accepts the request with the following HTTP
                            methods: GET and POST.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check that the application rejects and blocks the following requests with the HTTP
                            methods: TRACE, PUT and DELETE.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2018-08-07T09:56:11.228000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>