<control ref="AWS-LAMBDA-LOG-SPECIFICS" name="Increase log reports with serverless-specific information" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Organizations adopting serverless architectures, are encouraged to augment log reports with serverless-specific information such as:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Logging of API access keys related to successful/failed logins (authentication)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Attempts to invoke serverless functions with inadequate permissions (authorizations)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Successful/failed deployment of new serverless functions or configurations (change)&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Changes to function permissions or execution roles (change)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Changes to files or access permissions on relevant cloud storage services (change)&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Changes in function trigger definitions (change)&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Anomalous interaction or irregular flow between serverless functions (change)&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Changes to 3rd party dependencies (modules, libraries or APIs)&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Outbound connections initiated by serverless functions (network)&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Execution of serverless functions or access to data from an external 3rd party account not related to the main account to which the serverless application belongs (resource access)&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Serverless function execution timeouts (failure reports)&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Concurrent serverless function execution limits reached (failure reports)&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Organizations are also encouraged to adopt serverless application logic/code runtime tracing and debugging facilities in order to gain better understanding of the overall system and data flow. For example: AWS X-Ray&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt; To log more actions with the CloudTrail, we only have to create a trail as following:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ol&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Create a trail. By default, when you create a trail in a region in the CloudTrail console, the trail applies to all regions.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Create an Amazon S3 bucket or specify an existing bucket where you want the log files delivered. By default, log files from all regions in your account are delivered to the bucket that you specify.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Configure your trail to log read-only, write-only, or all management events, and all or a subset of data events. By default, trails log all management events and no data events.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Create an Amazon SNS topic to receive notifications when log files are delivered. Delivery notifications from all regions are sent to the topic that you specify.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Configure CloudWatch Logs to receive your logs from CloudTrail so that you can monitor for specific log events.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Change the encryption method for your log files from server-side encryption with Amazon S3-managed encryption keys (SSE-S3) to server-side encryption with AWS KMS–managed keys (SSE-KMS).&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Turn on integrity validation for log files. This enables the delivery of digest files that you can use to validate the integrity of log files after CloudTrail has delivered them.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Add tags (custom key-value pairs) to your trail.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ol&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references>
                        <reference name="AWS CLI describe-trails" url="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/reference/cloudtrail/describe-trails.html"/>
                        <reference name="AWS Lambda Metrics and Dimensions – CloudWatch" url="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonCloudWatch/latest/monitoring/aws-services-cloudwatch-metrics.html"/>
                        <reference name="AWS-X-Ray" url="https://aws.amazon.com/xray/"/>
                        <reference name="Creating a Trail For Your AWS Account" url="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/awscloudtrail/latest/userguide/cloudtrail-create-and-update-a-trail.html"/>
                        <reference name="Logging AWS Lambda API Calls by Using AWS CloudTrail" url="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/lambda/latest/dg/logging-using-cloudtrail.html"/>
                        <reference name="Logging AWS Serverless Application Repository API Calls with AWS CloudTrail" url="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/serverlessrepo/latest/devguide/logging-using-cloudtrail.html"/>
                        <reference name="Troubleshooting &amp; Monitoring Lambda-based Apps with CloudWatch" url="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/lambda/latest/dg/monitoring-functions.html"/>
                    </references>
                    <standards/>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;Check that the new logs are included in CloudTrail, we can get all trails with the following command: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;blockquote&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; aws cloudtrail describe-trails&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2019-03-25T16:40:59">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>