<control ref="CWE-654" name="Authenticate users (multi- or two-factor authentication [2FA])" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
  The application should ensure users have undergone an Identification and Verification (ID&amp;amp;V) process before allowing access to secret, sensitive or otherwise restricted data. For more sensitive applications hosting data or functionality requiring greater assurance over the identification of users, a multi- or two-factor authentication process is recommended. Together with asserting their identity and a password/phrase/PIN (something you know), such systems require additional factors, such as biometric validation (something you are) or a token (something you have). 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div&gt; 
 &lt;ul&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Implement multi-factor authentication for applications providing access to sensitive data or functionality, and for highly privileged user access (e.g. administrators).&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;This should utilize a factor such as a soft or hard-token verification in addition to the secret password/pass-phrase for example.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="164.312(d)" supportedStandardRef="hipaa-required"/>
                        <standard ref="IA-1" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="2.31" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="2.31" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="4.8" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-MASVS-L2"/>
                        <standard ref="4.8" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-MASVS-L2+R"/>
                        <standard ref="A2:2017-Broken Authentication" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check for the authentication(s) functions of the component.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check at least two of the following factors is used within the authentication
                            process.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Something that you are: mainly biometric characteristics of yourself as
                            fingerprint, facial recognition, iris recognition, etc.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Something that you know: a PIN, password, pass phrase, etc.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Something that you have: a hardware token, a card, a dongle, a mobile phone, etc.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:14.221000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>