<control ref="PCI-R1-1.1.6" name="1.1.6 - Document the business justification and approval for network changes " platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;These changes include the use of all services, protocols, and ports allowed. This
                        should
                        include documentation of security features implemented for those protocols considered to be
                        insecure.&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Compromises often happen due to unused or insecure service and ports, since these often
                        have known
                        vulnerabilities and many organizations don't patch vulnerabilities for the services,
                        protocols,
                        and ports
                        they don't use (even though the vulnerabilities are still present). By clearly defining and
                        documenting the
                        services, protocols, and ports that are necessary for business, organizations can ensure that
                        all other
                        services, protocols, and ports are disabled or removed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Approvals should be granted by personnel independent of the personnel managing the
                        configuration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;If insecure services, protocols, or ports are necessary for business, the risk posed by
                        use of
                        these protocols should be clearly understood and accepted by the organization, the use of the
                        protocol
                        should be justified, and the security features that allow these protocols to be used securely
                        should be
                        documented and implemented. If these insecure services, protocols, or ports are not necessary
                        for business,
                        they should be disabled or removed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;For guidance on services, protocols, or ports considered to be insecure, refer to
                        industry
                        standards and guidance (e.g., NIST, ENISA, OWASP, etc.).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="1.1.6" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;1.1.6.a Verify that firewall and router configuration standards include a
                            documented list of
                            all services, protocols and ports, including business justification and approval for each.
                            &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;1.1.6.b Identify insecure services, protocols, and ports allowed; and verify that
                            security
                            features are documented for each service. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;1.1.6.c Examine firewall and router configurations to verify that the documented
                            security
                            features are implemented for each insecure service, protocol, and port.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-04T14:49:09.219000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>