<control ref="PCI-R1-1.2.3" name="1.2.3 - Install perimeter firewalls between all wireless networks and CDE" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Configure these firewalls to deny or, if traffic is necessary for business purposes,
                        permit
                        only authorized traffic between the wireless environment and the cardholder data environment&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;The known (or unknown) implementation and exploitation of wireless technology within a
                        network is a
                        common path for malicious individuals to gain access to the network and cardholder data. If a
                        wireless
                        device or network is installed without the entity's knowledge, a malicious individual
                        could
                        easily and
                        "invisibly" enter the network. If firewalls do not restrict access from wireless
                        networks into
                        the CDE,
                        malicious individuals that gain unauthorized access to the wireless network can easily connect
                        to the CDE
                        and compromise account information.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Firewalls must be installed between all wireless networks and the CDE, regardless of
                        the purpose of
                        the environment to which the wireless network is connected. This may include, but is not limited
                        to,
                        corporate networks, retail stores, guest networks, warehouse environments, etc.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="1.2.3" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;1.2.3.a Examine firewall and router configurations to verify that there are
                            perimeter
                            firewalls installed between all wireless networks and the cardholder data environment. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;1.2.3.b Verify that the firewalls deny or, if traffic is necessary for business
                            purposes, permit
                            only authorized traffic between the wireless environment and the cardholder data
                            environment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-04T15:05:24.990000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>