<control ref="PCI-R1-1.2.1" name="1.2.1 - Restrict traffic into and from the CDE" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Allow only inbound and outbound traffic to that which is necessary for the cardholder
                        data
                        environment, and specifically deny all other traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Examination of all inbound and outbound connections allows for inspection and
                        restriction of
                        traffic based on the source and/or destination address, thus preventing unfiltered access
                        between untrusted
                        and trusted environments. This prevents malicious individuals from accessing the entity's
                        network via
                        unauthorized IP addresses or from using services, protocols, or ports in an unauthorized manner
                        (for
                        example, to send data they've obtained from within the entity's network out to an
                        untrusted
                        server).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Implementing a rule that denies all inbound and outbound traffic that is not
                        specifically needed
                        helps to prevent inadvertent holes that would allow unintended&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="1.2.1" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;1.2 Examine firewall and router configurations and perform the following to
                            verify that
                            connections are restricted between untrusted networks and system components in the
                            cardholder data
                            environment:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;1.2.1.a Examine firewall and router configuration standards to verify that they
                            identify inbound
                            and outbound traffic necessary for the cardholder data environment. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;1.2.1.b Examine firewall and router configurations to verify that inbound and
                            outbound traffic is
                            limited to that which is necessary for the cardholder data environment. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;1.2.1.c Examine firewall and router configurations to verify that all other inbound
                            and outbound
                            traffic is specifically denied, for example by using an explicit "deny all" or
                            an implicit
                            deny after
                            allow statement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-04T15:02:06.499000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>