<control ref="PCI-R10-10.4" name="10.4 - Use time-synchronization technologies to synchronize all critical system clocks and times" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>This technology must ensure that: &amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Critical systems have the correct and consistent time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; - Time
                        data is
                        protected.
                        &lt;br /&gt;- Time settings are received from industry-accepted time sources.
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Time synchronization technology is used to synchronize clocks on multiple systems. When
                        clocks are
                        not properly synchronized, it can be difficult, if not impossible, to compare log files from
                        different
                        systems and establish an exact sequence of event (crucial for forensic analysis in the event of
                        a breach).
                        For post-incident forensics teams, the accuracy and consistency of time across all systems and
                        the time of
                        each activity is critical in determining how the systems were compromised.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="10.4" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;10.4 Examine configuration standards and processes to verify that
                            time-synchronization
                            technology is implemented and kept current per PCI DSS Requirements 6.1 and 6.2.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;10.4.1.a Examine the process for acquiring, distributing and storing the correct
                            time within the
                            organization to verify that:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- Only the designated central time server(s) receives time signals from external
                            sources, and
                            time signals from external sources are based on International Atomic Time or UTC.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- Where there is more than one designated time server, the time servers peer with
                            one another to
                            keep accurate time,&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- Systems receive time information only from designated central time server(s).&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;10.4.1.b Observe the time-related system-parameter settings for a sample of system
                            components to
                            verify:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- Only the designated central time server(s) receives time signals from external
                            sources, and
                            time signals from external sources are based on International Atomic Time or UTC.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- Where there is more than one designated time server, the designated central time
                            server(s) peer
                            with one another to keep accurate time.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- Systems receive time only from designated central time server(s).&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;10.4.2.a Examine system configurations and time- synchronization settings to verify
                            that access
                            to time data is restricted to only personnel with a business need to access time data.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;10.4.2.b Examine system configurations, time synchronization settings and logs, and
                            processes to
                            verify that any changes to time settings on critical systems are logged, monitored, and
                            reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;10.4.3 Examine systems configurations to verify that the time server(s) accept time
                            updates from
                            specific, industry-accepted external sources (to prevent a malicious individual from
                            changing the clock).
                            Optionally, those updates can be encrypted with a symmetric key, and access control lists
                            can be created
                            that specify the IP addresses of client machines that will be provided with the time updates
                            (to prevent
                            unauthorized use of internal time servers).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T17:00:43.446000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>