<control ref="PCI-R11-11.2.3" name="11.2.3 - Perform internal and external scans after a significant change" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Perform internal and external scans, and rescans as needed, after any significant
                        change. Scans
                        must be performed by qualified personnel.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;The determination of what constitutes a significant change is highly dependent on the
                        configuration
                        of a given environment. If an upgrade or modification could allow access to cardholder data or
                        affect the
                        security of the cardholder data environment, then it could be considered significant.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Scanning an environment after any significant changes are made ensures that changes
                        were completed
                        appropriately such that the security of the environment was not compromised as a result of the
                        change. All
                        system components affected by the change will need to be scanned.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="11.2.3" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;11.2.3.a Inspect and correlate change control documentation and scan reports to
                            verify that
                            system components subject to any significant change were scanned. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;11.2.3.b Review scan reports and verify that the scan process includes rescans
                            until:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- For external scans, no vulnerabilities exist that are scored 4.0 or higher by the
                            CVSS.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- For internal scans, all "high risk" vulnerabilities as defined in PCI
                            DSS
                            Requirement 6.1 are
                            resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;11.2.3.c Validate that the scan was performed by a qualified internal resource(s)
                            or qualified
                            external third party and, if applicable, organizational independence of the tester exists
                            (not required to
                            be a QSA or ASV).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-07T21:44:02.864000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>