<control ref="PCI-R11-11.4" name="11.4 - Use intrusion detection systems to detect or prevent intrusions on the network" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Use intrusion-detection and/or intrusion-prevention techniques to detect and/or
                        prevent
                        intrusions into the network. Monitor all traffic at the perimeter of the cardholder data
                        environment as well
                        as at critical points in the cardholder data environment, and alert personnel to suspected
                        compromises.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Keep all intrusion-detection and prevention engines, baselines, and signatures up to
                        date.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Intrusion detection and/or intrusion prevention techniques (such as IDS/IPS) compare
                        the traffic
                        coming into the network with known "signatures" and/or behaviors of thousands of
                        compromise
                        types (hacker
                        tools, Trojans, and other malware), and send alerts and/or stop the attempt as it happens.
                        Without a
                        proactive approach to unauthorized activity detection, attacks on (or misuse of) computer
                        resources could go
                        unnoticed in real time. Security alerts generated by these techniques should be monitored so
                        that the
                        attempted intrusions can be stopped.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="11.4" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;11.4.a Examine system configurations and network diagrams to verify that
                            techniques (such as
                            intrusion-detection systems and/or intrusion-prevention systems) are in place to monitor all
                            traffic: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the perimeter of the cardholder data environment &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;At critical points in the cardholder data environment. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;11.4.b Examine system configurations and interview responsible personnel to confirm
                            intrusion-detection and/or intrusion-prevention techniques alert personnel of suspected
                            compromises. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;11.4.c Examine IDS/IPS configurations and vendor documentation to verify
                            intrusion-detection
                            and/or intrusion- prevention techniques are configured, maintained, and updated per vendor
                            instructions to
                            ensure optimal protection.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-07T21:53:30.373000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>