<control ref="PCI-R11-11.5" name="11.5 - Deploy a change-detection mechanism" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Deploy a change-detection mechanism (for example, file-integrity monitoring tools) to
                        alert
                        personnel to unauthorized modification (including changes, additions, and deletions) of critical
                        system
                        files, configuration files, or content files; and configure the software to perform critical
                        file
                        comparisons at least weekly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;A process to respond to any alerts generated by the change-detection solution must be
                        in place.&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Change-detection solutions such as file-integrity monitoring (FIM) tools check for
                        changes,
                        additions, and deletions to critical files, and notify when such changes are detected. If not
                        implemented
                        properly and the output of the change-detection solution monitored, a malicious individual could
                        add,
                        remove, or alter configuration file contents, operating system programs, or application
                        executables.
                        Unauthorized changes, if undetected, could render existing security controls ineffective and/or
                        result in
                        cardholder data being stolen with no perceptible impact to normal processing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="11.5" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;11.5.a&amp;nbsp;Verify the use of a change-detection mechanism by observing
                            system settings
                            and monitored files, as well as reviewing results from monitoring activities.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;Examples of files that should be monitored:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;System executables&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Application executables&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Configuration and parameter files&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Centrally stored, historical or archived, log and audit files&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additional critical files determined by entity (for example, through risk
                            assessment or
                            other means).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;11.5.b Verify the mechanism is configured to alert personnel to unauthorized
                            modification
                            (including changes, additions, and deletions) of critical files, and to perform critical
                            file comparisons
                            at least weekly. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;11.5.1 Interview personnel to verify that all alerts are investigated and resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-07T21:54:19.147000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>