<control ref="PCI-R12-12.6" name="12.6 - Implement a formal security awareness program" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Include:&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;Educate personnel upon hire and at least annually.&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Require personnel to acknowledge at least annually that they have read and understood
                        the
                        security policy and procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Implement a formal security awareness program to make all personnel aware of the
                        cardholder data
                        security policy and procedures.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;If personnel are not educated about their security responsibilities, security
                        safeguards and
                        processes that have been implemented may become ineffective through errors or intentional
                        actions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="12.6" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;12.6.a Review the security awareness program to verify it provides awareness to
                            all
                            personnel about the cardholder data security policy and procedures . &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.6.b Examine security awareness program procedures and documentation and perform
                            the following:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.6.1.a Verify that the security awareness program provides multiple methods of
                            communicating
                            awareness and educating personnel (for example, posters, letters, memos, web-based training,
                            meetings, and
                            promotions).&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.6.1.b Verify that personnel attend security awareness training upon hire and at
                            least
                            annually. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.6.1.c Interview a sample of personnel to verify they have completed awareness
                            training and are
                            aware of the importance of cardholder data security. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.6.2 Verify that the security awareness program requires personnel to
                            acknowledge, in writing
                            or electronically, at least annually, that they have read and understand the information
                            security policy&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-07T22:35:17.803000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>