<control ref="PCI-R12-12.8" name="12.8 - Maintain and implement policies and procedures to manage service providers with whom cardholder data is shared" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>Those have to be maintained as follows:&amp;nbsp;- Maintain a list of service providers
                        including a
                        description of the service provided.
                        &lt;br /&gt;- Maintain a written agreement that includes an acknowledgment that the service
                        providers are
                        responsible for the security of cardholder data the service providers possess or otherwise
                        store, process or
                        transmit on behalf of the customer, or to the extent that they could impact the security of the
                        customer's
                        cardholder data environment.
                        &lt;br /&gt;- Ensure there is an established process for engaging service providers including
                        proper due
                        diligence prior to engagement.
                        &lt;br /&gt;- Maintain a program to monitor service providers' PCI DSS compliance status
                        at
                        least annually.
                        &lt;br /&gt;- Maintain information about which PCI DSS requirements are managed by each service
                        provider,
                        and which are managed by the entity.
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="12.8" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;12.8 Through observation, review of policies and procedures, and review of
                            supporting
                            documentation, verify that processes are implemented to manage service providers with whom
                            cardholder data
                            is shared, or that could affect the security of cardholder data as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.8.1 Verify that a list of service providers is maintained and includes a
                            description of the
                            service provided. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.8.2 Observe written agreements and confirm they include an acknowledgment by
                            service
                            providers that they are responsible for the security of cardholder data the service
                            providers possess or
                            otherwise store, process or transmit on behalf of the customer, or to the extent that they
                            could impact
                            the security of the customer's cardholder data environment.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.8.3 Verify that policies and procedures are documented and implemented including
                            proper due
                            diligence prior to engaging any service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.8.4 Verify that the entity maintains a program to monitor its service providers'
                            PCI DSS
                            compliance status at least annually. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;12.8.5 Verify the entity maintains information about which PCI DSS requirements are
                            managed by
                            each service provider, and which are managed by the entity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-07T22:44:43.217000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>