<control ref="PCI-R2-2.1" name="2.1 - Change vendor-supplied defaults " platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>Make sure vendor-supplied defaults are changed. Remove or disable unnecessary default accounts
                        before
                        installing a system on the network.
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Malicious individuals (external and internal to an organization) often use vendor
                        default settings,
                        account names, and passwords to compromise operating system software, applications, and the
                        systems on which
                        they are installed. Because these default settings are often published and are well known in
                        hacker
                        communities, changing these settings will leave systems less vulnerable to attack.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Even if a default account is not intended to be used, changing the default password to
                        a strong
                        unique password and then disabling the account will prevent a malicious individual from
                        re-enabling the
                        account and gaining access with the default password.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Regarding wireless environments, they have to be implemented with sufficient security
                        configuration
                        (including changing default settings), wireless sniffers can eavesdrop on the traffic, easily
                        capture data
                        and passwords, and easily enter and attack the network.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;In addition, the key-exchange protocol for older versions of 802.11x encryption (Wired
                        Equivalent
                        Privacy, or WEP) has been broken and can render the encryption useless. Firmware for devices
                        should be
                        updated to support more secure protocols.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="2.1" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;2.1.a Choose a sample of system components, and attempt to log on (with system
                            administrator
                            help) to the devices and applications using default vendor-supplied accounts and passwords,
                            to verify that
                            ALL default passwords (including those on operating systems, software that provides security
                            services,
                            application and system accounts, POS terminals, and Simple Network Management Protocol
                            (SNMP) community
                            strings) have been changed. (Use vendor manuals and sources on the Internet to find
                            vendor-supplied
                            accounts/passwords.) &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.1.b For the sample of system components, verify that all unnecessary default
                            accounts
                            (including accounts used by operating systems, security software, applications, systems, POS
                            terminals,
                            SNMP, etc.) are removed or disabled. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.1.c Interview personnel and examine supporting documentation to verify that: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;nbsp;All vendor defaults (including default passwords on
                            operating systems,
                            software providing security services, application and system accounts, POS terminals, Simple
                            Network
                            Management Protocol (SNMP) community strings, etc.) are changed before a system is installed
                            on the
                            network. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;nbsp;Unnecessary default accounts (including accounts used
                            by
                            operating
                            systems, security software, applications, systems, POS terminals, SNMP, etc.) are removed or
                            disabled
                            before a system is installed on the network&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.1.1.a Interview responsible personnel and examine supporting documentation to
                            verify that: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Encryption keys were changed from default at installation &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Encryption keys are changed anytime anyone with knowledge of the keys
                            leaves the
                            company or changes positions. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.1.1.b Interview personnel and examine policies and procedures to verify: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Default SNMP community strings are required to be changed upon
                            installation. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Default passwords/passphrases on access points are required to be
                            changed upon
                            installation. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.1.1.c Examine vendor documentation and login to wireless devices, with system
                            administrator
                            help, to verify: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Default SNMP community strings are not used. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Default passwords/passphrases on access points are not used. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.1.1.d Examine vendor documentation and observe wireless configuration settings to
                            verify
                            firmware on wireless devices is updated to support strong encryption for: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Authentication over wireless networks &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Transmission over wireless networks. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.1.1.e Examine vendor documentation and observe wireless configuration settings to
                            verify other
                            security- related wireless vendor defaults were changed, if applicable.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-04T16:06:35.141000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>