<control ref="CWE-319-TRANSPORT" name="4.1 - Use strong cryptography and security protocols to safeguard sensitive cardholder" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Use strong cryptography and security protocols to safeguard sensitive cardholder data
                        during
                        transmission over open, public networks, including the following:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Only trusted keys and certificates are accepted.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- The protocol in use only supports secure versions or configurations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- The encryption strength is appropriate for the encryption methodology in use.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Sensitive information must be encrypted during transmission over public networks,
                        because it is
                        easy and common for a malicious individual to intercept and/or divert data while in transit.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Secure transmission of cardholder data requires using trusted keys/certificates, a
                        secure protocol
                        for transport, and proper encryption strength to encrypt cardholder data. Connection requests
                        from systems
                        that do not support the required encryption strength, and that would result in an insecure
                        connection,
                        should not be accepted.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Note that some protocol implementations (such as SSL, SSH v1.0, and early TLS) have
                        known
                        vulnerabilities that an attacker can use to gain control of the affected system. Whichever
                        security protocol
                        is used, ensure it is configured to use only secure versions and configurations to prevent use
                        of an
                        insecure connection-for example, by using only trusted certificates and supporting only
                        strong
                        encryption
                        (not supporting weaker, insecure protocols or methods).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Verifying that certificates are trusted (for example, have not expired and are issued
                        from a
                        trusted source) helps ensure the integrity of the secure connection.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Generally, the web page URL should begin with &amp;quot;HTTPS&amp;quot; and/or the web
                        browser
                        display a padlock icon somewhere in the window of the browser. Many TLS certificate vendors also
                        provide a
                        highly visible verification seal-sometimes referred to as a "security seal,"
                        &amp;quot;secure
                        site seal,&amp;quot;
                        or "secure trust seal")-which may provide the ability to click on the seal to
                        reveal information
                        about the
                        website.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Refer to industry standards and best practices for information on strong cryptography
                        and secure
                        protocols (e.g., NIST SP 800-52 and SP 800-57, OWASP, etc.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="4.1" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                        <standard ref="A3:2017-Sensitive Data Exposure" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                        <standard ref="A8:2017-Insecure Deserialization" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.1.a&lt;/b&gt; Identify all locations where cardholder data is
                            transmitted or
                            received over open, public networks. Examine documented standards and compare to system
                            configurations to
                            verify the use of security protocols and strong cryptography for all locations.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.1.b&lt;/b&gt; Review documented policies and procedures to verify
                            processes are
                            specified for the following: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;For acceptance of only trusted keys and/or certificates &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the protocol in use to only support secure versions &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;and
                            configurations (that insecure versions or configurations are not supported) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;For implementation of proper encryption strength per the encryption
                            methodology in use
                            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.1.c&lt;/b&gt; Select and observe a sample of inbound and outbound
                            transmissions as
                            they occur (for example, by observing system processes or network traffic) to verify that
                            all cardholder
                            data is encrypted with strong cryptography during transit.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.1.d&lt;/b&gt; Examine keys and certificates to verify that only trusted
                            keys and/or
                            certificates are accepted. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.1.e&lt;/b&gt; Examine system configurations to verify that the protocol
                            is implemented
                            to use only secure configurations and does not support insecure versions or configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4.1.f&lt;/b&gt; Examine system configurations to verify that the proper
                            encryption
                            strength is implemented for the encryption methodology in use. (Check vendor
                            recommendations/best
                            practices.) &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;4.1.g For TLS implementations, examine system configurations to verify that TLS is
                            enabled
                            whenever cardholder data is transmitted or received. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;For example, for browser-based implementations: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;"HTTPS" appears as the browser Universal Record Locator
                            (URL) protocol,
                            and &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cardholder data is only requested if "HTTPS" appears as part
                            of the URL.
                            &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;4.1.h If SSL/early TLS is used, perform testing procedures in Appendix A2:
                            Additional PCI DSS
                            Requirements for Entities using SSL/Early TLS.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T09:19:07.555000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>