<control ref="PCI-R5-5.3" name="5.3 - Ensure that anti-virus mechanisms are always actively running" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;They should not be &amp;nbsp;disabled or altered by users, unless specifically
                        authorized by
                        management on a case-by-case basis for a limited time period.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Anti-virus that continually runs and is unable to be altered will provide persistent
                        security
                        against malware.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Use of policy-based controls on all systems to ensure anti-malware protections cannot
                        be altered or
                        disabled will help prevent system weaknesses from being exploited by malicious software.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Additional security measures may also need to be implemented for the period of time
                        during which
                        anti-virus protection is not active-for example, disconnecting the unprotected system from
                        the
                        Internet
                        while the anti-virus protection is disabled, and running a full scan after it is re-enabled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="5.3" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;5.3.a Examine anti-virus configurations, including the master installation of
                            the software
                            and a sample of system components, to verify the anti-virus software is actively running.
                            &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;5.3.b Examine anti-virus configurations, including the master installation of the
                            software and a
                            sample of system components, to verify that the anti-virus software cannot be disabled or
                            altered by
                            users.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;5.3.c Interview responsible personnel and observe processes to verify that
                            anti-virus software
                            cannot be disabled or altered by users, unless specifically authorized by management on a
                            case-by-case
                            basis for a limited time period.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T09:53:45.720000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>