<control ref="PCI-R6-6.2" name="6.2 - Protect all the systems from known vulnerabilities" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Ensure that all system components and software are protected from known
                        vulnerabilities by
                        installing applicable vendor-supplied security patches. Install critical security patches within
                        one month
                        of release.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;There is a constant stream of attacks using widely published exploits, often called
                        &amp;quot;zero
                        day&amp;quot; (an attack that exploits a previously unknown vulnerability), against otherwise
                        secured
                        systems. If the most recent patches are not implemented on critical systems as soon as possible,
                        a malicious
                        individual can use these exploits to attack or disable a system, or gain access to sensitive
                        data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Prioritizing patches for critical infrastructure ensures that high-priority systems and
                        devices are
                        protected from vulnerabilities as soon as possible after a patch is released. Consider
                        prioritizing patch
                        installations such that security patches for critical or at-risk systems are installed within 30
                        days, and
                        other lower-risk patches are installed within 2-3 months.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;This requirement applies to applicable patches for all installed software, including
                        payment
                        applications (both those that are PA-DSS validated and those that are not).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="6.2" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;6.2.a Examine policies and procedures related to security- patch installation to
                            verify
                            processes are defined for: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Installation of applicable critical vendor-supplied security patches
                            within one month
                            of release. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Installation of all applicable vendor-supplied security patches within
                            an appropriate
                            time frame (for example, within three months).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;6.2.b For a sample of system components and related software, compare the list of
                            security
                            patches installed on each system to the most recent vendor security-patch list, to verify
                            the following:
                            &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;That applicable critical vendor-supplied security patches are installed
                            within one
                            month of release. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;All applicable vendor-supplied security patches are installed within an
                            appropriate
                            time frame (for example, within three months).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T12:18:58.262000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>