<control ref="PCI-R8-8.3.1" name="8.3.1 - Secure non-console administrative access with multi-factor authentication" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;This requirement is intended to apply to all personnel with administrative access to
                        the CDE.
                        This requirement applies only to personnel with administrative access and only for non-console
                        access to the
                        CDE; it does not apply to application or system accounts performing automated functions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;If the entity does not use segmentation to separate the CDE from the rest of their
                        network, an
                        administrator could use multi-factor authentication either when logging onto the CDE network or
                        when logging
                        onto a system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;If the CDE is segmented from the rest of the entity's network, an administrator
                        would
                        need to use
                        multi-factor authentication when connecting to a CDE system from a non-CDE network. Multi-factor
                        authentication can be implemented at network level or at system/application level; it does not
                        have to be
                        both. If the administrator uses MFA when logging into the CDE network, they do not also need to
                        use MFA to
                        log into a particular system or application within the CDE.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="8.3.1" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;8.3.1.a Examine network and/or system configurations, as applicable, to verify
                            multi-factor
                            authentication is required for all non-console administrative access into the CDE.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;8.3.1.b Observe a sample of administrator personnel login to the CDE and verify
                            that at least two
                            of the three authentication methods are used.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T15:12:12.344000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>