<control ref="PCI-R8-8.6" name="8.6 - When using non password/passphrase authentication-based methods, assign them properly." platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Where other authentication mechanisms are used (for example, physical or logical
                        security
                        tokens, smart cards, certificates, etc.), use of these mechanisms must be assigned as follows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Authentication mechanisms must be assigned to an individual account and not shared
                        among multiple
                        accounts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Physical and/or logical controls must be in place to ensure only the intended account
                        can use
                        that mechanism to gain access.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;If user authentication mechanisms such as tokens, smart cards, and certificates can be
                        used by
                        multiple accounts, it may be impossible to identify the individual using the authentication
                        mechanism.
                        Having physical and/or logical controls (for example, a PIN, biometric data, or a password) to
                        uniquely
                        identify the user of the account will prevent unauthorized users from gaining access through use
                        of a shared
                        authentication mechanism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="8.6" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;8.6.a Examine authentication policies and procedures to verify that procedures
                            for using
                            authentication mechanisms such as physical security tokens, smart cards, and certificates
                            are defined and
                            include: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Authentication mechanisms are assigned to an individual account and not
                            shared among
                            multiple accounts. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Physical and/or logical controls are defined to ensure only the intended
                            account can
                            use that mechanism to gain access. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;8.6.b Interview security personnel to verify authentication mechanisms are assigned
                            to an account
                            and not shared among multiple accounts. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;8.6.c Examine system configuration settings and/or physical controls, as
                            applicable, to verify
                            that controls are implemented to ensure only the intended account can use that mechanism to
                            gain access.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T15:33:45.532000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>