<control ref="PCI-R8-8.7" name="8.7 - Restrict access to databases with cardholder data" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Access should be restricted as follows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- All user access to, user queries of, and user actions on databases are through
                        programmatic
                        methods.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Only database administrators have the ability to directly access or query databases.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Application IDs for database applications can only be used by the applications (and
                        not by
                        individual users or other non-application processes).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Without user authentication for access to databases and applications, the potential for
                        unauthorized or malicious access increases, and such access cannot be logged since the user has
                        not been
                        authenticated and is therefore not known to the system. Also, database access should be granted
                        through
                        programmatic methods only (for example, through stored procedures), rather than via direct
                        access to the
                        database by end users (except for DBAs, who may need direct access to the database for their
                        administrative
                        duties).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="8.7" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;8.7.a Review database and application configuration settings and verify that all
                            users are
                            authenticated prior to access. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;8.7.b Examine database and application configuration settings to verify that all
                            user access to,
                            user queries of, and user actions on (for example, move, copy, delete), the database are
                            through
                            programmatic methods only (for example, through stored procedures). &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;8.7.c Examine database access control settings and database application
                            configuration settings to
                            verify that user direct access to or queries of databases are restricted to database
                            administrators. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;8.7.d Examine database access control settings, database application configuration
                            settings, and
                            the related application IDs to verify that application IDs can only be used by the
                            applications (and not
                            by individual users or other processes).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T15:35:05.538000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>