<control ref="PCI-R9-9.3" name="9.3 - Control physical access for onsite personnel to sensitive areas" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Control physical access for onsite personnel to sensitive areas as follows:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Access must be authorized and based on individual job function.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Access is revoked immediately upon termination, and all physical access mechanisms,
                        such as keys,
                        access cards, etc., are returned or disabled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Controlling physical access to sensitive areas helps ensure that only authorized
                        personnel with a
                        legitimate business need are granted access.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;When personnel leave the organization, all physical access mechanisms should be
                        returned or
                        disabled promptly (as soon as possible) upon their departure, to ensure personnel cannot gain
                        physical
                        access to sensitive areas once their employment has ended.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.3" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;9.3.a For a sample of onsite personnel with physical access to sensitive areas,
                            interview
                            responsible personnel and observe access control lists to verify that: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Access to the sensitive area is authorized. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Access is required for the individual's job function. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.3.b Observe personnel accessing sensitive areas to verify that all personnel are
                            authorized
                            before being granted access. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.3.c Select a sample of recently terminated employees and review access control
                            lists to verify
                            the personnel do not have physical access to sensitive areas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T15:57:47.417000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>