<control ref="PCI-R9-9.4" name="9.4 - Implement procedures to identify, authorize and revoke access to visitors" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;- Visitors are authorized before entering, and escorted at all times within, areas
                        where
                        cardholder data is processed or maintained.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Visitors are identified and given a badge or other identification that expires and
                        that visibly
                        distinguishes the visitors from onsite personnel. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Visitors are asked to surrender the badge or identification before leaving the
                        facility or at the
                        date of expiration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- A visitor log is used to maintain a physical audit trail of visitor activity to the
                        facility as
                        well as computer rooms and data centers where cardholder data is stored or transmitted. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Document the visitor's name, the firm represented, and the onsite personnel
                        authorizing physical
                        access on the log.&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Retain this log for a minimum of three months, unless otherwise restricted by law.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Visitor controls are important to reduce the ability of unauthorized and malicious
                        persons to gain
                        access to facilities (and potentially, to cardholder data).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Visitor controls ensure visitors are identifiable as visitors so personnel can monitor
                        their
                        activities, and that their access is restricted to just the duration of their legitimate visit.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Ensuring that visitor badges are returned upon expiry or completion of the visit
                        prevents malicious
                        persons from using a previously authorized pass to gain physical access into the building after
                        the visit
                        has ended.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;A visitor log documenting minimum information on the visitor is easy and inexpensive to
                        maintain
                        and will assist in identifying physical access to a building or room, and potential access to
                        cardholder
                        data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.4" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;9.4 Verify that visitor authorization and access controls are in place as
                            follows: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.4.1.a Observe procedures and interview personnel to verify that visitors must be
                            authorized
                            before they are granted access to, and escorted at all times within, areas where cardholder
                            data is
                            processed or maintained. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.4.1.b Observe the use of visitor badges or other identification to verify that a
                            physical token
                            badge does not permit unescorted access to physical areas where cardholder data is processed
                            or
                            maintained. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.4.2.a Observe people within the facility to verify the use of visitor badges or
                            other
                            identification, and that visitors are easily distinguishable from onsite personnel. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.4.2.b Verify that visitor badges or other identification expire. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.4.3 Observe visitors leaving the facility to verify visitors are asked to
                            surrender their badge
                            or other identification upon departure or expiration. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.4.4.a Verify that a visitor log is in use to record physical access to the
                            facility as well as
                            computer rooms and data centers where cardholder data is stored or transmitted. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.4.4.b Verify that the log contains: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The visitor's name, &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The firm represented, and &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The onsite personnel authorizing physical access. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.4.4.c Verify that the log is retained for at least three months.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T16:01:02.821000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>