<control ref="PCI-R9-9.6" name="9.6 - Strictly control internal and external media distribution" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;- Classify media so the sensitivity of the data can be determined:&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;It is important that media be identified such that its classification status can be
                        easily
                        discernible. Media not identified as confidential may not be adequately protected or may be lost
                        or stolen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Send the media by secured courier or other delivery method that can be accurately
                        tracked:&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Media may be lost or stolen if sent via a non-trackable method such as regular postal
                        mail. Use of
                        secure couriers to deliver any media that contains cardholder data allows organizations to use
                        their
                        tracking systems to maintain inventory and location of shipments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Ensure management approves any and all media that is moved from a secured area
                        (including when
                        media is distributed to individuals):&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Without a firm process for ensuring that all media movements are approved before the
                        media is
                        removed from secure areas, the media would not be tracked or appropriately protected, and its
                        location would
                        be unknown, leading to lost or stolen media.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.6" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;9.6 Verify that a policy exists to control distribution of media, and that the
                            policy covers
                            all distributed media including that distributed to individuals. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.6.1 Verify that all media is classified so the sensitivity of the data can be
                            determined.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.6.2.a Interview personnel and examine records to verify that all media sent
                            outside the
                            facility is logged and sent via secured courier or other delivery method that can be
                            tracked.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.6.2.b Select a recent sample of several days of offsite tracking logs for all
                            media, and verify
                            tracking details are documented.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.6.3 Select a recent sample of several days of offsite tracking logs for all
                            media. From
                            examination of the logs and interviews with responsible personnel, verify proper management
                            authorization
                            is obtained whenever media is moved from a secured area (including when media is distributed
                            to
                            individuals).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T16:07:21.228000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>