<control ref="PCI-R9-9.8" name="9.8 - Securely destroy the media when it is no longer needed" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;- Shred, incinerate, or pulp hard-copy materials so that cardholder data cannot be
                        reconstructed. Secure storage containers used for materials that are to be destroyed. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Render cardholder data on electronic media unrecoverable so that cardholder data
                        cannot be
                        reconstructed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;If steps are not taken to destroy information contained on hard disks, portable drives,
                        CD/DVDs, or
                        paper prior to disposal, malicious individuals may be able to retrieve information from the
                        disposed media,
                        leading to a data compromise. For example, malicious individuals may use a technique known as
                        "dumpster
                        diving," where they search through trashcans and recycle bins looking for information they
                        can
                        use to launch
                        an attack.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Securing storage containers used for materials that are going to be destroyed prevents
                        sensitive
                        information from being captured while the materials are being collected. For example,
                        "to-be-shredded"
                        containers could have a lock preventing access to its contents or physic ally prevent access to
                        the inside
                        of the container.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Examples of methods for securely destroying electronic media include secure wiping,
                        degaussing, or
                        physical destruction (such as grinding or shredding hard disks).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.8" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;9.8 Examine the periodic media destruction policy and verify that it covers all
                            media and
                            defines requirements for the following: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hard-copy materials must be crosscut shredded, incinerated, or pulped
                            such that there
                            is reasonable assurance the hard- copy materials cannot be reconstructed. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Storage containers used for materials that are to be destroyed must be
                            secured. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cardholder data on electronic media must be rendered unrecoverable
                            (e.g., via a secure
                            wipe program in accordance with industry-accepted standards for secure deletion, or by
                            physically
                            destroying the media). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.8.1.a Interview personnel and examine procedures to verify that hard-copy
                            materials are
                            crosscut shredded, incinerated, or pulped such that there is reasonable assurance the
                            hard-copy materials
                            cannot be reconstructed. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.8.1.b Examine storage containers used for materials that contain information to
                            be destroyed to
                            verify that the containers are secured. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.8.2 Verify that cardholder data on electronic media is rendered unrecoverable
                            (e.g., via a
                            secure wipe program in accordance with industry-accepted standards for secure deletion, or
                            by physically
                            destroying the media).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T16:10:02.439000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>