<control ref="PCI-R9-9.9.2" name="9.9.2 - Periodically inspect device surfaces to detect tampering or substitution" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Regular inspections of devices will help organizations to more quickly detect
                        tampering or
                        replacement of a device, and thereby minimize the potential impact of using fraudulent devices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;The type of inspection will depend on the device-for example, photographs of
                        devices
                        that are known
                        to be secure can be used to compare a device's current appearance with its original
                        appearance
                        to see
                        whether it has changed. Another option may be to use a secure marker pen, such as a UV light
                        marker, to mark
                        device surfaces and device openings so any tampering or replacement will be apparent. Criminals
                        will often
                        replace the outer casing of a device to hide their tampering, and these methods may help to
                        detect such
                        activities. Device vendors may also be able to provide security guidance and "how to"
                        guides to
                        help
                        determine whether the device has been tampered with.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;The frequency of inspections will depend on factors such as location of device and
                        whether the
                        device is attended or unattended. For example, devices left in public areas without supervision
                        by the
                        organization's personnel may have more frequent inspections than devices that are kept in
                        secure
                        areas or
                        are supervised when they are accessible to the public. The type and frequency of inspections is
                        determined
                        by the merchant, as defined by their annual risk-assessment process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.9.2" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;9.9.2.a Examine documented procedures to verify processes are defined to include
                            the
                            following: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Procedures for inspecting devices &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Frequency of inspections. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;9.9.2.b Interview responsible personnel and observe inspection processes to verify:
                            &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Personnel are aware of procedures for inspecting devices. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;All devices are periodically inspected for evidence of tampering and
                            substitution.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T16:18:20.839000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>