<control ref="PCI-R2-A1.2" name="A1.2 - Restrict each entity's access and privileges to its own CDE." platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;To ensure that access and privileges are restricted such that each merchant or
                        service provider
                        has access only to their own environment, consider the following:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;1. Privileges of the merchant's or service provider's web server user ID;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;2. Permissions granted to read, write, and execute files;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;3. Permissions granted to write to system binaries;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;4. Permissions granted to merchant's and service provider's log files; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;5. Controls to ensure one merchant or service provider cannot monopolize system
                        resources.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="A1.2" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;A1.2.a Verify the user ID of any application process is not a privileged user
                            (root/admin).
                            &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;A1.2.b Verify each entity (merchant, service provider) has read, write, or execute
                            permissions
                            only for files and directories it owns or for necessary system files (restricted via file
                            system
                            permissions, access control lists, chroot, jailshell, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;Important: An entity's files may not be shared by group. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;A1.2.c Verify that an entity's users do not have write access to shared
                            system
                            binaries. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;A1.2.d Verify that viewing of log entries is restricted to the owning entity. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;A1.2.e To ensure each entity cannot monopolize server resources to exploit
                            vulnerabilities (for
                            example, error, race, and restart conditions resulting in, for example, buffer overflows),
                            verify
                            restrictions are in place for the use of these system resources: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;Disk space&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;Bandwidth&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;Memory&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;CPU&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-04T16:40:09.782000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>