<control ref='GOOGLE-SQL01' name='Enable SSL channel encryption to connect to the database' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Enable and configure SSL encryption with the certificates to connect to the SQL database. This
                        way only users with the appropriate certificate can connect to the SQL database. Remediation:
                        You can create up to 10 client certificates for each instance. If you lose the private key for a
                        certificate, you must create a new one; the private key cannot be recovered.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ol&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Go to the Cloud SQL Instances page in the &lt;a
                        href="https://console.cloud.google.com/sql/instances"&gt;Google Cloud Platform Console&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click the instance name to open its Instance details page.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Select the SSL tab.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the SSL Connections section, click Allow only SSL connection to enforce that only
                        SSL connections can connect to the instances. (This step is not required. However, if you do not
                        require SSL for all connections, any issue with your SSL configuration can cause all connections
                        to default silently to unencrypted.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the Client Certificates section, click Create a Client Certificate.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the New client certificate dialog box, give the certificate a name unique for this
                        instance and click Add.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the first section of the New SSL certificate created dialog box, click the link to
                        download the private key to a file named client-key.pem. (Important: Store this private key
                        securely. If you lose it, you must create a new client certificate.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the second section, click the link to download the client certificate to a file
                        named client-cert.pem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the third section, click the link to download the server certificate to a file
                        named server-ca.pem.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click Close.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ol&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Google Cloud docs: MySQL SSL configuration' url='https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/configure-ssl-instance?-419#introduction' />
          </references>
          <standards />
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Go to the Cloud SQL Instances page in the Google Cloud Platform Console.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Click the instance name to open its Instance details page.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Select the SSL tab.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;In the SSL Connections section, check that the SSL Connections are configured and
                            enabled correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>