<control ref='GOOGLE-STO03' name='Use apropriate names for the buckets' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Google Cloud Storage requests refer to buckets and objects by their names. As a result, even
                        though ACLs will prevent unauthorized third parties from operating on buckets or objects, a
                        third party can attempt requests with bucket or object names and determine their existence by
                        observing the error responses.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        It can then be possible for information in bucket or object names to be leaked. If you are
                        concerned about the privacy of your bucket or object names, you should take appropriate
                        precautions, such as:
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Choosing bucket and object names that are difficult to guess. For example, a bucket
                        named mybucket-gtbytul3 is random enough that unauthorized third parties cannot feasibly guess
                        it or enumerate other bucket names from it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Avoiding use of sensitive information as part of bucket or object names. For example,
                        instead of naming your bucket mysecretproject-prodbucket, name it somemeaninglesscodename-prod.
                        In some applications, you may want to keep sensitive metadata in custom Google Cloud Storage
                        headers such as x-goog-meta, rather than encoding the metadata in object names.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Google Cloud docs: Best practices Storage' url='https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/best-practices#security' />
          </references>
          <standards />
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>Check that all buckets are named appropriately.
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>