<control ref='hippa-ac-07' name='Implement procedures for creating, changing, and safeguarding passwords' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>&lt;p&gt;Implement procedures for creating, changing and safeguarding passwords.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The creation and modification of a password, should be secure and the new password should comply with minimum security requirements. For example, when the password is changed, the system should request the old password. Another example is the new password is at least a minimum number of characters and at least one number, plus one uppercase character and one lowercase character.&lt;/p&gt;</desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='HIPAA Security Standards: Administrative Safeguards' url='https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/ocr/privacy/hipaa/administrative/securityrule/adminsafeguards.pdf' />
            <reference name='OWASP Proactive Controls C6: Implement Digital Identity' url='https://owasp-top-10-proactive-controls-2018.readthedocs.io/en/latest/c6-implement-digital-identity.html' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='164.308(A)(5)(D)' supportedStandardRef='hipaa-addressable' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>	&lt;p&gt;How to Test: &lt;/p&gt;


 What characters are permitted and forbidden for use within a password? Is the user required to use characters from different character sets such as lower and uppercase letters, digits and special symbols? 


 How often can a user change their password? How quickly can a user change their password after a previous change? Users may bypass password history requirements by changing their password 5 times in a row so that after the last password change they have configured their initial password again. 


 When must a user change their password? After 90 days? After account lockout due to excessive log on attempts? 


 How often can a user reuse a password? Does the application maintain a history of the user&amp;#8217;s previous used 8 passwords? 


 How different must the next password be from the last password? 


 Is the user prevented from using his username or other account information (such as first or last name) in the password?</steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2019-08-09T14:30:49.000'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>