<control ref="CWE-209-USERNAME-REG" name="Prevent username and email enumeration in the registration process" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Enumeration of usernames and/or email addresses within an application is a common attack, aiding
                        in conducting brute-force attacks against users, and with potential privacy issues where the
                        username is considered to be personally identifiable information (PII).
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Messages returned to the user during the registration process should not reveal any
                        information about existing users of the system. For example, if a user attempts to register with
                        an email address that is already associated with a user, the application should not reveal this
                        to them.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;To protect privacy and prevent user enumeration, the application should always respond
                        with the same message indicating an email has been sent to the user's address regardless of the
                        status of that email address or username, and direct them to follow the instructions therein to
                        complete the process.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Where the username or email address is already in use, the email can advise the user
                        of the recovery process.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Where the username and email are unique and new, the email can contain a link to
                        complete the process.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        The prevents an attacker without access to the victim's email address from enumerating whether
                        they are registered in the application.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.4.2" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="AC-16" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="2.18" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-1"/>
                        <standard ref="2.18" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="2.18" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Go to the registration function of the component.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Register a user &amp;nbsp;A with the email email@example.com.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Restart the registration process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Try to register a user B with the same email --&amp;gt; email@example.com.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check there is no information provided revealing the email already exists.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt; Alternatively, if a configured email has been used check that an email has been
                            sent to that email address informing user A that another user has tried to register with
                            their email.
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:17.765000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>