<weakness ref="CWE-611" name="Improper Restriction of XML External Entity Reference ('XXE')" state="0" impact="100">
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps></steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references>
                            <reference name="CWE-611: Improper Restriction of XML External Entity Reference ('XXE')" url="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/611.html"/>
                        </references>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:15.823000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                    <desc>The software processes an XML document that can contain XML entities with URIs that resolve to
                        documents outside of the intended sphere of control, causing the product to embed incorrect
                        documents into its output.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;br /&gt;XML documents optionally contain a Document Type Definition (DTD), which, among
                        other features, enables the definition of XML entities. It is possible to define an entity by
                        providing a substitution string in the form of a URI. The XML parser can access the contents of
                        this URI and embed these contents back into the XML document for further processing. By
                        submitting an XML file that defines an external entity with a file:// URI, an attacker can cause
                        the processing application to read the contents of a local file. For example, a URI such as
                        &amp;quot;file:///c:/winnt/win.ini&amp;quot; designates (in Windows) the file C:\Winnt\win.ini,
                        or file:///etc/passwd designates the password file in Unix-based systems.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Using URIs with other schemes such as http://, the attacker can force the application to make
                        outgoing requests to servers that the attacker cannot reach directly, which can be used to
                        bypass firewall restrictions or hide the source of attacks such as port scanning. Once the
                        content of the URI is read, it is fed back into the application that is processing the XML. This
                        application may echo back the data (e.g. in an error message), there by exposing the file
                        contents.
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                </weakness>