<control ref="PWD-RECOVER-OTP" name="Send time expired one time password/token (TOTP) in email" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        The password/account recovery process must have equivalent security to the normal authentication
                        process. It should be resistant to brute-force or network monitoring attacks. Reset over email
                        presents a risk of monitoring and interception, these threats can in part by mitigated through
                        the following process:
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Create a unique token or password that compromises at least 128 bits of provably
                        random data.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;This token should be emailed to the registered email address of the user; for example
                        in&amp;nbsp;form of a one time password, or a unique identifier in a URL.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;The token should expire after a short period of time (long enough for the user to
                        receive and process the email - 15 minutes at most and preferably less).&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;When the user provides the token, the application should verify their identity (for
                        example through use of a 'secret question', or verification of recent activity or transaction
                        information).&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;The password or token must be single use; the user must be required to choose a new
                        password and the token should be immediately invalidated.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards/>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Perform the password reset process implemented by the component.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check the recovery is done by using a one time token on an email.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;For this one time token check it cannot be reused and it cannot be used after a
                            short period of time.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:17.446000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>