<control ref='Hydras-AWS-S3-7.4' name='Encrypt sensitive data at rest with KMS' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Amazon Simple Storage Service is storage for the Internet. It is designed to make web-scale
                        computing easier for developers.
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;Amazon S3 has a simple web services interface that you can use to store and retrieve
                        any amount of data, at any time, from anywhere on the web. It gives any developer access to the
                        same highly scalable, reliable, fast, inexpensive data storage infrastructure that Amazon uses
                        to run its own global network of web sites.
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;To ensure that sensitive data is encrypted at rest you can use AWS KMS–managed
                        keys (SSE-KMS). This provides several advantages:&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;You can create and manage the CMK encryption keys yourself.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;You can use a single CMK to encrypt and decrypt log files for multiple accounts across
                        all regions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;You have control over who can use your key for encrypting and decrypting CloudTrail
                        log files. You can assign permissions for the key to the users in your organization according to
                        your requirements.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;You have enhanced security. With this feature, in order to read log files, you now
                        need to meet two conditions: 1) you must have S3 read permission on the bucket, and 2) you must
                        be granted decrypt permission by the CMK policy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;It is recommended to encrypt all sensitive data with SSE-KMS to avoid undue
                        disclosure of information and provide an extra layer of security.
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;The following example shows how to upload data using AWS KMS Encryption:
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        aws s3api put-object --bucket &amp;lt;my_bucket&amp;gt; --server-side-encryption aws:kms
                        --ssekms-key-id &amp;lt;kms_key_id&amp;gt; --key &amp;lt;object_to_upload&amp;gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Content provided by &lt;a href="https://hydrasit.com" target="_blank"&gt; Hydras IT LTD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references />
          <standards />
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;blockquote&gt;
                            aws s3api head-object --bucket &amp;lt;my_bucket&amp;gt; --key &amp;lt;my_key&amp;gt;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;Look for the line &amp;quot;ServerSideEncryption&amp;quot; and verify
                            that it is set to &amp;quot;aws:kms&amp;quot; which indicates KMS Encryption.
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2019-04-01T07:51:15.000'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>