<threat ref="CAPEC-188" name="Attacker gains access to sensitive data by modifying the application's expected behavior" state="Expose" source="MANUAL" owner="" library="">
                            <desc>An attacker discovers the structure, function, and composition of an object, resource,
                                or system by using a variety of analysis techniques to effectively determine how the
                                analyzed entity was constructed or operates. The goal of reverse engineering is often to
                                duplicate the function, or a part of the function, of an object in order to duplicate or
                                &amp;quot;back engineer&amp;quot; some aspect of its functioning.&amp;nbsp;
                                &lt;div&gt;
                                &lt;br /&gt;
                                &lt;/div&gt;
                                &lt;div&gt;
                                Reverse engineering techniques can be applied to mechanical objects, electronic devices,
                                or software, although the methodology and techniques involved in each type of analysis
                                differ widely. When adversaries are reverse engineering software, methodologies fall
                                into two broad categories, 'white box' and 'black box.' White box techniques involve
                                methods which can be applied to a piece of software when an executable or some other
                                compiled object can be directly subjected to analysis, revealing at least a portion of
                                its machine instructions that can be observed upon execution.
                                &lt;/div&gt;
                                &lt;div&gt;
                                &lt;br /&gt;
                                &lt;/div&gt;
                                &lt;div&gt;
                                'Black Box' methods involve interacting with the software indirectly, in the absence of
                                the ability to measure, instrument, or analyze an executable object directly. Such
                                analysis typically involves interacting with the software at the boundaries of where the
                                software interfaces with a larger execution environment, such as input-output vectors,
                                libraries, or APIs.
                                &lt;/div&gt;
                            </desc>
                            <riskRating confidentiality="25" integrity="25" availability="100" easeOfExploitation="100"/>
                            <references/>
                            <controls>
                                <control ref="MASVS-8.10" mitigation="16"/>
                                <control ref="MASVS-8.11" mitigation="16"/>
                                <control ref="MASVS-8.4" mitigation="17"/>
                                <control ref="MASVS-8.5" mitigation="17"/>
                                <control ref="MASVS-8.6" mitigation="17"/>
                                <control ref="MASVS-8.7" mitigation="17"/>
                            </controls>
                            <weaknesses>
                                <weakness ref="MASVS-EMULATION-TOOLS">
                                    <controls>
                                        <control ref="MASVS-8.11" mitigation="16"/>
                                        <control ref="MASVS-8.5" mitigation="17"/>
                                        <control ref="MASVS-8.7" mitigation="17"/>
                                    </controls>
                                </weakness>
                                <weakness ref="MASVS-REVERSE-ENGINEERING-TOOLS">
                                    <controls>
                                        <control ref="MASVS-8.10" mitigation="16"/>
                                        <control ref="MASVS-8.4" mitigation="17"/>
                                        <control ref="MASVS-8.6" mitigation="17"/>
                                    </controls>
                                </weakness>
                            </weaknesses>
                        </threat>