<control ref='D2.1.1' name='Ensure that only containers which are required to communicate with each other are linked together' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>By default, all network traffic is allowed between containers on the same host on the default
                        network bridge. If your containers should communicate with each other, you can create a custom
                        network and only join containers that need to communicate to that custom network. Alternatively,
                        link only specific containers together that require communication.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Rationale:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        By default, unrestricted network traffic is enabled between all containers on the same host on
                        the default network bridge. Thus, each container has the potential of reading all packets across
                        the container network on the same host. This might lead to an unintended and unwanted disclosure
                        of information to other containers. Hence, create a custom network and only join containers that
                        need to communicate to that custom network or link only specific containers together that
                        require communication.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        You can follow the Docker documentation to create a custom network and only join containers that
                        need to communicate to that custom network. The --icc parameter only applies to the default
                        docker bridge, if custom networks are used then the approach of segmenting networks should be
                        adopted instead.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Alternatively, follow the Docker documentation and link specific containers using the --link
                        flag.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Note: Docker warns users not to use the --link flag unless absolutely necessary, because it is a
                        legacy Docker feature and it may eventually be removed.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Impact:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        You have to manage the custom networks.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Docker docs: Bridge' url='https://docs.docker.com/network/bridge/' />
            <reference name='Docker docs: Links' url='https://docs.docker.com/network/links/' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='2.1' supportedStandardRef='Level 1 - Docker' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>The docker network inspect command returns information about a network and can be used as
                            follows:&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step 1:&lt;/b&gt; Ensure the default bridge network has no containers:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            docker network inspect bridge&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Step 2:&lt;/b&gt; Check your custom network for joined containers:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            docker network inspect
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>