<control ref="CWE-798-CLIENT" name="Authentication credentials should be saved in a cryptographically secure store" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Single or automated sign-on from thick client applications can be facilitated in a number of
                        ways; local/client-side storage of credentials is considered an insecure option due to the risk
                        of exposure of the credentials at the client-side.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;If possible, avoid storing authentication credentials on the client at all. Instead,
                        consider use of keys, certificates, or other cryptographically secure token unique to the
                        client-side instance and controlled by the client-side. &amp;nbsp;For example, a unique key
                        could be issued to each client where the 'stay logged in' or similar function has been selected.
                        These individual keys can then be expired or revoked from the server-side automatically or by
                        the user as required.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;If credentials must be stored, then they should be stored in a cryptographically
                        secure encrypted store.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Where possible, system provided stores should be used; for example, iOS and Android
                        provide password stores, as does MacOS/OS X's Keychain.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.2.4" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="9.3.1" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="9.4.2" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="9.4.3" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="AC-16" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="CM-6" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="2.13" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="2.21" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="2.13" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="2.21" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="2.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-MASVS-L1"/>
                        <standard ref="2.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-MASVS-L1+R"/>
                        <standard ref="2.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-MASVS-L2"/>
                        <standard ref="2.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-MASVS-L2+R"/>
                        <standard ref="A3:2017-Sensitive Data Exposure" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Identify the functions of the component which are storing sensitive data, in
                            particular authentication credentials.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Confirm that system provided stores (such as the Mac OS X Keychain) are used.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            If not, and a separate encryption process is in use, it should be noted it is considered bad
                            practice to store passwords in recoverable form. Verify the following:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Data is encrypted before being stored (e.g. in memory before writing to any
                            persistent storage)&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Data is erased in memory before release&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Libraries or code used to encrypt the data are reputable and provably secure (i.e.
                            have undergone proper review) and are implemented in line with recommendations (e.g. correct
                            use of a strong PRNG).&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Ideally a public-key cryptography should be used.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Keys to decrypt the data must not be stored on the device with the data.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Confirm how the data will be accessed or unlocked; and that security is equivalent
                            to the stored credentials. e.g. is the password saved using a master password, PIN
                            protection or similar?&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:18.930000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>