<weakness ref="CWE-937" name="Third party libraries contain security weaknesses" state="0" impact="100">
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps></steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references>
                            <reference name="OWASP Top 10 - A9" url="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10_2013-A9-Using_Components_with_Known_Vulnerabilities"/>
                        </references>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:11.657000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                    <desc>In theory, it ought to be easy to figure out if you are currently using any vulnerable
                        components or libraries. Unfortunately, vulnerability reports for commercial or open source
                        software do not always specify exactly which versions of a component are vulnerable in a
                        standard, searchable way. Further, not all libraries use an understandable version numbering
                        system. Worst of all, not all vulnerabilities are reported to a central clearinghouse that is
                        easy to search, although sites like CVE and NVD are becoming easier to search.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;br /&gt;Determining if you are vulnerable requires searching these databases, as well as
                        keeping abreast of project mailing lists and announcements for anything that might be a
                        vulnerability. If one of your components does have a vulnerability, you should carefully
                        evaluate whether you are actually vulnerable by checking to see if your code uses the part of
                        the component with the vulnerability and whether the flaw could result in an impact you care
                        about.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;br /&gt;Component vulnerabilities can cause almost any type of risk imaginable, ranging from
                        the trivial to sophisticated malware designed to target a specific organization. Components
                        almost always run with the full privilege of the application, so flaws in any component can be
                        serious.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                </weakness>