<control ref="ASVS-16.6" name="Do not store user files under the web root" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
  Storage of user-controlled content in folders accessible through the web-server increases the risk of exposure, and also facilitates attacks relying on the upload and execution, or distribution, of malicious content.&amp;nbsp; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div&gt; 
 &lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div&gt;
  In the case of proprietary user data, it may also expose the restricted data to compromise through direct browsing or direct object reference manipulation if access controls are not securely implemented 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div&gt; 
 &lt;ul&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Store uploaded files and other content in segregated folders outside of the web root directory tree to prevent direct access.&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;File content that is intended to be accessed by users from the client-side should be streamed with appropriate MIME types.&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure appropriate permissions are applied to the files and the folders; they should only be readable by the relevant service accounts, and should not be executable.&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Ideally, the folder containing the files should not be accessible through the web-application even in the event of a directory traversal or server-side file include vulnerability.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;</desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="AC-6" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="16.6" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="16.6" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="A5:2017-Broken Access Control" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Identify the data sources that the application is using to retrieve data (other
                            systems, upload methods, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check this data is being stored outside of the WebRoot so there will be no way to
                            access them from external locations.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-11-30T13:04:03.010000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>