<control ref='Hydras-AWS-SNS-02' name='Enforce HTTPS to encrypt notifications' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>To send messages to an HTTPS endpoint through a topic, you must subscribe the endpoint to the
                        Amazon SNS topic. You specify the endpoint using its URL. To subscribe to a topic, you can use
                        the Amazon SNS console, the sns-subscribe command, or the Subscribe API action.
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;ol&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Sign in to the AWS Management Console and open the Amazon SNS console at
                        https://console.aws.amazon.com/sns/v2/home.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the left navigation pane, click Topics and then select the topic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click the Other actions drop-down list and select Subscribe to topic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the Protocol drop-down list, select HTTPS.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the Endpoint box, paste in the URL for the endpoint that you want the topic to send
                        messages to and then click Create subscription.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;For the Subscription request received! message, click Close.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Your new subscription's Subscription ID displays PendingConfirmation. When you confirm
                        the subscription, Subscription ID will display the subscription ID.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ol&gt;Content provided by
                        &lt;a href="https://hydrasit.com" target="_blank"&gt; Hydras IT LTD&lt;/a&gt;.
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references />
          <standards />
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Sign in to the AWS Management Console and open the Amazon SNS console at
                            https://console.aws.amazon.com/sns/v2/home.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;In the left navigation panel, click Topics and then select the topic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Click the Other actions drop-down list and select Subscribe to topic.I&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;In the Protocol drop-down list, check that the protocol HTTPS is selected.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2019-04-01T07:51:15.000'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>