<control ref="ASVS-3.2" name="Terminate user sessions on the server-side" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        User sessions may end for a number of reasons; they may choose to log out, the session may be
                        subject to an active or inactive timeout, they may be logged out due to concurrency
                        restrictions, or the session may be revoked due to automated or manual intervention in response
                        to a security or other event (e.g. suspicious behavior or system maintenance).
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        In all cases, the user session must be terminated at the server-side, not solely at the
                        client-side (for example by deleting or reissuing a session ID token/cookie).
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Revoke user sessions at the server-side.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Redirect users to the login page, or provide a login prompt to them in context.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Where possible, ensure the session is not reused by the application server.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.4.2" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="AC-11" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="AC-12" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="3.2" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-1"/>
                        <standard ref="3.2" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="3.2" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="A2:2017-Broken Authentication" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check the session is terminated at the server side and not using code in the
                            browser:&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Authenticate as a user.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Using an intercepting proxy, the Web Developer Console,&amp;nbsp;or other tool;
                            intercept the browser request and server response, and determine which cookies or other
                            tokens are used to maintain session state. Alternatively, capture an authenticated
                            application request for replay.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Terminate the session using the application logout function&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Replay the captured request or add the session tokens back into the session to see
                            if the application response with authenticated data.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            To change or set the Session ID and otherwise modify browser requests, use an intercepting
                            proxy (e.g. OWASP Zap, Burp or Fiddler), or browser extensions such as Cookie Manager or
                            Tamper Data.
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:20.252000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>