<control ref="CWE-485-PREPROD" name="Ensure personal and other sensitive data is not exposed in pre-production environments" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Pre-production environments should not expose personally identifiable information (PII) or other
                        sensitive information. Often, such environments are populated with production data for testing
                        or other purposes. &amp;nbsp;Security weaknesses, either in the software or controls around
                        access to pre-prod systems, can unnecessarily expose sensitive data. This is often a breach of
                        legal and commercial requirements, including various governmental data protection and privacy
                        acts, and industry regulations such as those required by the Payments Card Industry (PCI).
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Where test data is derived from production data, the following must be observed:
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ol&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Data masking or obfuscation techniques must be used to anonymize the data used in
                        pre-production. &amp;nbsp;For example, all but the start and end of a credit card number must be
                        removed/replaced&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;No real personally identifiable information (PII) or other sensitive data should be
                        present in Pre-prod. &amp;nbsp;For example, names, dates of birth, and other personal
                        information must be removed, randomized, or replaced.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Only data that has been processed and anonymized should be transferred into pre-prod;
                        ideally representative test data should be generated rather than relying even on obfuscated
                        production data.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ol&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="A3:2017-Sensitive Data Exposure" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check the data used on the pre-production environment is not duplicated from
                            production.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Where production data is modified for use in pre-production, review the
                            transformations applied to ensure all PII and other sensitive data is removed, obfuscated,
                            or otherwise scrubbed.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Verify that pre-prod data is not real, and does not constitute PII data.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Consider use of 'canaries' or other deliberately injected values in production to
                            perform random searches in pre-prod environments for data that has been inappropriately
                            migrated or used.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:18.121000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>