<threat ref="CAPEC-1-ANDROID" name="Malicious applications gain access to unauthorised data or perform unauthorised actions" state="Expose" source="MANUAL" owner="" library="">
                            <desc>Attackers could use malicious mobile applications to attack legitimate applications
                                that export their components improperly. The attacks and consequences of improperly
                                exporting a component may depend on the exported component: If access to an exported
                                Activity is not restricted, any application will be able to launch the activity.&amp;nbsp;
                                &lt;div&gt;
                                &lt;br /&gt;
                                &lt;/div&gt;
                                &lt;div&gt;
                                This may allow a malicious application to gain access to sensitive information, modify
                                the internal state of the application, or trick a user into interacting with the victim
                                application whilst believing they are still interacting with the malicious application.
                                If access to an exported Service is not restricted, any application may start and bind
                                to the Service.&amp;nbsp;
                                &lt;/div&gt;
                                &lt;div&gt;
                                &lt;br /&gt;
                                &lt;/div&gt;
                                &lt;div&gt;
                                Depending on the exposed functionality, this may allow a malicious application to
                                perform unauthorized actions, gain access to sensitive information, or corrupt the
                                internal state of the application. If access to a Content Provider is not restricted to
                                only the expected applications, then malicious applications might be able to access the
                                sensitive data. Note that in Android before 4.2, the Content Provider is automatically
                                exported unless it has been explicitly declared as NOT exported.
                                &lt;/div&gt;
                            </desc>
                            <riskRating confidentiality="75" integrity="75" availability="1" easeOfExploitation="75"/>
                            <references/>
                            <controls>
                                <control ref="CAPEC-1-ANDROID" mitigation="25"/>
                                <control ref="CAPEC-1-ANDROID-CONT" mitigation="25"/>
                                <control ref="CAPEC-1-ANDROID-SRV" mitigation="25"/>
                                <control ref="CWE-20" mitigation="25"/>
                            </controls>
                            <weaknesses>
                                <weakness ref="CWE-732">
                                    <controls>
                                        <control ref="CAPEC-1-ANDROID" mitigation="25"/>
                                        <control ref="CAPEC-1-ANDROID-CONT" mitigation="25"/>
                                        <control ref="CAPEC-1-ANDROID-SRV" mitigation="25"/>
                                    </controls>
                                </weakness>
                                <weakness ref="CWE-20">
                                    <controls>
                                        <control ref="CWE-20" mitigation="25"/>
                                    </controls>
                                </weakness>
                            </weaknesses>
                        </threat>