<control ref="CSD_PWD-REC-Q" name="Security questions must not violate privacy laws and processes must provide equivalent security to normal authentication" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        It is common for application to utilize 'security questions' as additional identity verification
                        steps in the registration, authentication, and recovery processes. While these questions provide
                        additional assurance, they should not be considered a true secret, or of equal security to the
                        user's password. Furthermore, it is important that laws and legislation around private and
                        personally identifiable information (PII) are observed, and the risk of disclosure of the
                        security questions and answers should be considered.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Ensure the security questions do not violate privacy laws (e.g. asking for a SSN or
                        Cardholder Data)&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Questions and answers must be prevent from malicious recovery (e.g. enumeration or
                        brute-force attacks)&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;The questions, and processes in which they are used, must be strong enough to provide
                        equivalence to the main authentication process.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Processes involving the security questions must prevent an attacker with publicly
                        available (or common personal) information about the victim from accessing their account. For
                        example, date of birth, place of birth, birthdate, and mother's maiden name are common pieces of
                        security information that are not truly secret.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Consider allowing the user to define their own security questions (challenges) and
                        answers (responses) with guidance.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="AC-2" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="IA-1" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="2.24" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-1"/>
                        <standard ref="2.24" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="2.24" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check the question set the application has for security questions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check their compliance against the &lt;a
                            href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Choosing_and_Using_Security_Questions_Cheat_Sheet"
                            rel="nofollow"&gt;OWASP guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references>
                            <reference name="OWASP - Choosing and Using Security Questions" url="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Choosing_and_Using_Security_Questions_Cheat_Sheet"/>
                        </references>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-11-24T12:41:07.955000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>