<control ref="CSD-PWD-OFF-CHAN" name="Use a secure recovery token to reset an account password (such as a TOTP)" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        The password/account recovery process must have equivalent security to the normal authentication
                        process. It should be resistant to brute-force or network monitoring attacks.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Having identified the user through secret questions/answers, the application should
                        proceed with a secure reset process.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Passwords should not be sent in plain text (for example in an email), as they may be
                        intercepted or monitored.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Instead, the application should verify the user's identity, and use a time-limited one
                        time password token (TOTP) from the user.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Alternatively, the application could require the user enters a soft-token (e.g. Google
                        authenticator), a mobile-push / SMS code, or previously established off-line recovery mechanism
                        (for example a list of pre-defined recovery codes). It should be noted that use of a random
                        value in an e-mail or SMS has known weaknesses, and should be considered a less secure option.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;When the user provides the token, the application should verify their identity (for
                        example through use of a 'secret question', or verification of recent activity or transaction
                        information).&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;The application should then require they choose a new password or phrase in line with
                        the chosen policy.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.2.4" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="IA-1" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="2.22" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-1"/>
                        <standard ref="2.22" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="2.22" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Navigate through the password recovery process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check that a Time-Based One-Time Password token or a push message with a unique,
                            one use-only and valid for a given time (typically 1h) token is used.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-11-24T12:29:57.542000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>