<control ref="CWE-922-AUTH" name="Clear sensitive and authenticated data from client-side storage" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Sensitive data should not be persistently stored at the client-side due to the risk of exposure.
                        However, during normal application operation, authenticated and other sensitive data is passed,
                        stored in transient form, and displayed to users. It is important that any such temporary
                        storage is purged in a timely manner and actively at the end of a user session.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Sensitive data (including any authenticated content)&amp;nbsp;stored on client side
                        objects such as the browser DOM should be cleared.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;This data should be removed actively at the end of user session (e.g. using the logout
                        function), and where possible cleared through hard termination of the browser (e.g. closing the
                        window or tab without using the proper application function).&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Ensure any storage used during application interaction is temporary, and automatically
                        cleared by the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Where possible, set expiration times on client-side data to prevent accidental or
                        malicious storage or disclosure.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="12.2.1" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="CA-8" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="SI-10" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="SI-14" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="5.26" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="5.26" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Access the application as an authenticated user.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Manually or programmatically browse the site and use authenticated functionality&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;In particular, identify application functionality where sensitive or secret data
                            is held by the browser. This may include credit card PAN or other data held in the viewstate
                            or DOM while data is gathered from the user, for example.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Ensure this data is not stored persistently (e.g. on disk, in persistent cookies,
                            HTML5 stores, Flash! or Silverlight storage etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Review local storage in the browser Web Developer Console during and after use of
                            the application. For example, review the HTML5 objects localStorage and sessionStorage for
                            any sensitive data which is saved and not deleted after the logout&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Alternatively, a Javascript console can be used with the command: s&lt;i&gt;essionStorage//Storage
                            {length: 0}localStorage//Storage {length: 0}&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-11-30T10:29:56.771000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>