<control ref="CWE-525-WEB" name="Disable autocompletion of sensitive data" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Auto-completion or pre-filling of sensitive details by the browser implies that those details
                        are stored in plaintext or a reversible format. This may be in violation of security
                        best-practice, or application security expectations. The application should attempt to mitigate
                        this risk by requesting the browser does not cache or store sensitive data such as credit card
                        PANs and CV2s, personally identifiable information (PII) or other secret data.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;All forms handling sensitive data should be protected using the autocomplete=off HTML
                        directive at the form or field level.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Issue browser specific directives to request auto-fill or completion is disabled; The
                        AUTOCOMPLETE attribute should be set to &amp;quot;OFF&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        It should be noted that compliance with these requests at the client-side is optional, and many
                        browsers and clients override these directives to use operating system, browser, or third party
                        password managers or key-safes to store secrets.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="SC-1" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="9.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-1"/>
                        <standard ref="9.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="9.1" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Review HTML forms to ensure the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt;autocomplete=off&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;directive
                            is used where secrets such as password or sensitive data is submitted.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Using a browser:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Inspect the HTML source in the browser&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Ensure the autocomplete=off attribute is set at the field, form, or page level.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Using an intercepting proxy (e.g. OWASP Zap, BurpSuite)&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Browse the site through the proxy&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Review HTML sources for the autocomplete attribute&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;br /&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:21.695000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>