<control ref="CWE-922" name="Do not store sensitive data on client side" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Browsers and extensions provide a number of local storage options to persist data during HTTP
                        interactions, including (but not limited to) Cookies, HTML5 local storage, session storage,
                        IndexedDB, Flash! cookies, and Silverlight isolated storage. These storage options may all be
                        accessed by subsequent users of the browser or computer, and some have experienced security
                        vulnerabilities providing unauthorized and/or remote access to their contents. It is important
                        that sensitive, private, and otherwise restricted data is handled with care at the client-side,
                        and is not stored in insecure locations which may expose it to attack.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Do not store sensitive data in any kind of persistent, client-side storage.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Review any application or browser layer caching or temporary storage to ensure it
                        doesn't expose data.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="10.1.2" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="SA-8" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="SI-1" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="9.9" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-1"/>
                        <standard ref="1.10" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="9.9" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="1.10" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="9.9" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="A3:2017-Sensitive Data Exposure" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Identify application functionality where sensitive or secret data is held by the
                            browser. This may include credit card PAN or other data held in the viewstate or DOM while
                            data is gathered from the user, for example.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Ensure this data is not stored persistently (e.g. on disk, in persistent cookies,
                            HTML5 stores, Flash! or Silverlight storage etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Review local storage in the browser Web Developer Console during and after use of
                            the application.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-11-30T11:14:07.850000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>