<control ref="PCI-R3-3.6.6" name="3.6.6 - Implement secure manual key-management operations" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;If manual clear-text cryptographic key-management operations are used, these
                        operations must be
                        managed using split knowledge and dual control.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Split knowledge and dual control of keys are used to eliminate the possibility of one
                        person having
                        access to the whole key. This control is applicable for manual key-management operations, or
                        where key
                        management is not implemented by the encryption product.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Split knowledge is a method in which two or more people separately have key components,
                        where each
                        person knows only their own key component, and the individual key components convey no knowledge
                        of the
                        original cryptographic key.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Dual control requires two or more people to perform a function, and no single person
                        can access or
                        use the authentication materials of another.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="3.6.6" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;3.6.6.a Verify that manual clear-text key-management procedures specify
                            processes for the
                            use of the following: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Split knowledge of keys, such that key components are under the control
                            of at least
                            two people who only have knowledge of their own key components; AND &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dual control of keys, such that at least two people are required to
                            perform any
                            key-management operations and no one person has access to the authentication materials (for
                            example,
                            passwords or keys) of another. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;3.6.6 b Interview personnel and/or observe processes to verify that manual
                            clear-text keys are
                            managed with: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Split knowledge, AND &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dual control&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T09:08:25.385000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>