<control ref="PCI-R3-3.6.5" name="3.6.5 - Retirement or replacement  of keys when their integrity has been weakened" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Retirement or replacement (for example, archiving, destruction, and/or revocation) of
                        keys as
                        deemed necessary when the integrity of the key has been weakened (for example, departure of an
                        employee with
                        knowledge of a clear-text key component), or keys are suspected of being compromised.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Keys that are no longer used or needed, or keys that are known or suspected to be
                        compromised,
                        should be revoked and/or destroyed to ensure that the keys can no longer be used. If such keys
                        need to be
                        kept (for example, to support archived, encrypted data) they should be strongly protected.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;The encryption solution should provide for and facilitate a process to replace keys
                        that are due
                        for replacement or that are known to be, or suspected of being, compromised.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="3.6.5" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;3.6.5.a Verify that key-management procedures specify processes for the
                            following: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The retirement or replacement of keys when the integrity of the key has
                            been weakened
                            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The replacement of known or suspected compromised keys. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Any keys retained after retiring or replacing are not used for
                            encryption
                            operations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;3.6.5.b Interview personnel to verify the following processes are implemented: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Keys are retired or replaced as necessary when the integrity of the key
                            has been
                            weakened, including when someone with knowledge of the key leaves the company. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Keys are replaced if known or suspected to be compromised. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Any keys retained after retiring or replacing are not used for
                            encryption operations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T09:06:49.384000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>