<control ref="AWS-LAMBDA-C5" name="Ensure you store your encryption keys in a Key Management System" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;AWS Key Management Service (KMS) is a managed service that makes it easy for you to create and control the encryption keys used to encrypt your data, and uses FIPS 140-2 validated hardware security modules to protect the security of your keys. AWS Key Management Service is integrated with most other AWS services to help you protect the data you store with these services. AWS Key Management Service is also integrated with AWS CloudTrail to provide you with logs of all key usage to help meet your regulatory and compliance needs.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Verify that you are using the Key Management Service. You can see a list of your customer managed keys in the AWS Management Console.&lt;br /&gt; To view your CMKs (console): &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ol&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Sign in to the AWS Management Console and open the AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;In the left navigation pane, choose Encryption keys.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;For Region, choose the appropriate AWS Region. Do not use the region selector in the navigation bar (top right corner). The console shows all the CMKs in your AWS account in the chosen region, including customer-managed and AWS managed CMKs. The page displays the alias, key ID, status, and creation date for each CMK.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ol&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;If you need to create a CMK:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ol&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Sign in to the AWS Management Console and open the AWS Key Management Service (AWS KMS) console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/kms.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;To change the AWS Region, use the Region selector in the upper-right corner of the page.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;In the navigation pane, choose Customer managed keys.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Choose Create key.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Type an alias for the CMK. The alias name cannot begin with aws/. The aws/ prefix is reserved by Amazon Web Services to represent AWS managed CMKs in your account.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;An alias is a display name that you can use to identify the CMK. We recommend that you choose an alias that indicates the type of data you plan to protect or the application you plan to use with the CMK.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Aliases are required when you create a CMK in the AWS Management Console. They are optional when you use the CreateKey operation.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;(Optional) Type a description for the CMK.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;We recommend that you choose a description that explains the type of data you plan to protect or the application you plan to use with the CMK.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Choose Next.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;(Optional) Type a tag key and an optional tag value. To add more than one tag to the CMK, choose Add tag.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;When you add tags to your AWS resources, AWS generates a cost allocation report with usage and costs aggregated by tags. For information about tagging CMKs, see Tagging Keys.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Choose Next.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Select the IAM users and roles that can administer the CMK.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;(Optional) To prevent the selected IAM users and roles from deleting this CMK, in the Key deletion section at the bottom of the page, clear the Allow key administrators to delete this key check box.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Choose Next.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Select the IAM users and roles that can use the CMK for cryptographic operations.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;(Optional) You can allow other AWS accounts to use this CMK for cryptographic operations. To do so, in the Other AWS accounts section at the bottom of the page, choose Add another AWS account and enter the AWS account identification number of an external account. To add multiple external accounts, repeat this step.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Choose Next.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Review the key policy document that was created from your choices. You can edit it, too.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Choose Finish to create the CMK.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ol&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references>
                        <reference name="AWS Key management service documentation" url="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/kms/latest/developerguide/getting-started.html"/>
                    </references>
                    <standards/>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Check that you are using the Key Management Service. To view a list of your customer managed keys in the AWS Management Console.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;To view your CMKs (console):&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;ol&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Sign in to the AWS Management Console and open the AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/.&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;In the left navigation pane, choose Encryption keys.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;For Region, choose the appropriate AWS Region. Do not use the region selector in the navigation bar (top right corner). The console shows all the CMKs in your AWS account in the chosen region, including customer-managed and AWS managed CMKs. The page displays the alias, key ID, status, and creation date for each CMK.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;/ol&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2019-03-25T16:40:59">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>