<control ref='D5.14' name='Ensure &apos;on-failure&apos; container restart policy is set to &apos;5&apos;' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Using the --restart flag in docker run command you can specify a restart policy for how a
                        container should or should not be restarted on exit. You should choose the on-failure restart
                        policy and limit the restart attempts to 5.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Rationale:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        If you indefinitely keep trying to start the container, it could possibly lead to a denial of
                        service on the host. It could be an easy way to do a distributed denial of service attack
                        especially if you have many containers on the same host. Additionally, ignoring the exit status
                        of the container and always attempting to restart the container leads to non-investigation of
                        the root cause behind containers getting terminated. If a container gets terminated, you should
                        investigate the reason behind it instead of just attempting to restart it indefinitely. Thus, it
                        is recommended to use on-failure restart policy and limit it to a maximum of 5 restart attempts.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        If a container is desired to be restarted on its own, then, for example, you could start the
                        container as below:&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        docker run --detach --restart=on-failure:5 nginx&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Impact:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        The container would attempt to restart only 5 times.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Docker docs: restart policies' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/commandline/run/#restart-policies-restart' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='5.14' supportedStandardRef='Level 1 - Docker' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;blockquote&gt;
                            docker ps --quiet --all | xargs docker inspect --format '{{ .Id }}: RestartPolicyName={{
                            .HostConfig.RestartPolicy.Name }} MaximumRetryCount={{
                            .HostConfig.RestartPolicy.MaximumRetryCount }}'&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;If the above command returns RestartPolicyName=always, then the system is not
                            configured as desired and hence this recommendation is non-compliant.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;If the above command returns RestartPolicyName=no or just RestartPolicyName=, then
                            the restart policies are not being used and the container would never be restarted on its
                            own. This recommendation is then Not Applicable and can be assumed to be compliant.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;If the above command returns RestartPolicyName=on-failure, then verify that the
                            number of restart attempts is set to 5 or less by looking at MaximumRetryCount.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>