<control ref='D5.24' name='Ensure cgroup usage is confirmed' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>It is possible to attach to a particular cgroup on container run. Confirming cgroup usage
                        would ensure that containers are running under defined cgroups.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Rationale:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        System administrators typically define cgroups under which containers are supposed to run. Even
                        if cgroups are not explicitly defined by the system administrators, containers run under docker
                        cgroup by default. At run-time, it is possible to attach to a different cgroup other than the
                        one that was expected to be used. This usage should be monitored and confirmed. By attaching to
                        a different cgroup than the one that is expected, excess permissions and resources might be
                        granted to the container and thus, can prove to be unsafe.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Do not use --cgroup-parent option in docker run command unless needed.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Impact:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        None.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Docker docs: custom cgroups' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/run/#specify-custom-cgroups' />
            <reference name='Docker redhat: resource management' url='https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux/6/html/Resource_Management_Guide/ch01.html' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='5.24' supportedStandardRef='Level 1 - Docker' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;blockquote&gt;
                            docker ps --quiet --all | xargs docker inspect --format '{{ .Id }}: CgroupParent={{
                            .HostConfig.CgroupParent }}'&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            The above command would return the cgroup under which the containers are running. If it is
                            blank, it means containers are running under default docker cgroup. In that case, this
                            recommendation is compliant. If the containers are found to be running under cgroup other
                            than the one that was expected, this recommendation is non-compliant.
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>