<control ref='D5.10' name='Ensure memory usage for container is limited' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>By default, all containers on a Docker host share the resources equally. By using the resource
                        management capabilities of Docker host, such as memory limit, you can control the amount of
                        memory that a container may consume.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Rationale:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        By default, container can use all of the memory on the host. You can use memory limit mechanism
                        to prevent a denial of service arising from one container consuming all of the host's resources
                        such that other containers on the same host cannot perform their intended functions. Having no
                        limit on memory can lead to issues where one container can easily make the whole system unstable
                        and as a result unusable.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Run the container with only as much memory as required. Always run the container using the
                        --memory argument. For example, you could run a container as below:&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        docker run --interactive --tty --memory 256m centos /bin/bash&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/blockquote&gt;In the above example, the container is started with a memory limit of 256 MB.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Note: Please note that the output of the below command would return values in scientific
                        notation if memory limits are in place.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        docker inspect --format='{{.Config.Memory}}' 7c5a2d4c7fe0&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/blockquote&gt;For example, if the memory limit is set to 256 MB for the above container
                        instance, the output of the above command would be 2.68435456e+08 and NOT 256mb. You should
                        convert this value using a scientific calculator or programmatic methods. Impact: If you do not
                        set proper limits, the container process may have to starve.
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Docker docs: run metrics' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/admin/runmetrics/' />
            <reference name='Docker docs: run options' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/commandline/run/#options' />
            <reference name='Goldmann blog: run options' url='https://goldmann.pl/blog/2014/09/11/resource-management-in-docker/' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='5.10' supportedStandardRef='Level 1 - Docker' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;blockquote&gt;
                            docker ps --quiet --all | xargs docker inspect --format '{{ .Id }}: Memory={{
                            .HostConfig.Memory }}'&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            If the above command returns 0, it means the memory limits are not in place. If the above
                            command returns a non-zero value, it means memory limits are in place.
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>