<control ref='D1.2' name='Ensure the container host has been Hardened' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Containers run on a Linux host. A container host can run one or more containers. It is of
                        utmost importance to harden the host to mitigate host security misconfiguration.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Rationale:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        You should follow infrastructure security best practices and harden your host OS. Keeping the
                        host system hardened would ensure that the host vulnerabilities are mitigated. Not hardening the
                        host system could lead to security exposures and breaches.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        You may consider various CIS Security Benchmarks for your container host. If you have other
                        security guidelines or regulatory requirements to adhere to, please follow them as appropriate
                        in your environment.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        Additionally, you can run a kernel with grsecurity and PaX. This would add many safety checks,
                        both at compile-time and run-time. It is also designed to defeat many exploits and has powerful
                        security features. These features do not require Docker-specific configuration, since these
                        security features apply system-wide, independent of containers.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Impact:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        None.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Docker benchmarks' url='https://learn.cisecurity.org/benchmarks' />
            <reference name='Docker docs: other kernel security features' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/security/security/#other-kernel-security-features' />
            <reference name='Docker docs: Security' url='https://docs.docker.com/engine/security/security/' />
            <reference name='Grsecurity' url='https://grsecurity.net/' />
            <reference name='Grsecurity book' url='https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Grsecurity' />
            <reference name='Grsecurity pax' url='https://pax.grsecurity.net/' />
            <reference name='Pax' url='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PaX' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='1.2' supportedStandardRef='Level 1 - Linux Host OS' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>Ensure that the host specific security guidelines are followed. Ask the system
                            administrators which security benchmark the current host system complies with.&amp;nbsp;
                            &lt;div&gt;
                            Ensure that the host systems actually complies with that host specific security benchmark.
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>