<control ref='GOOGLE-VM01' name='Allow Virtual IP of the Microsoft host node' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Allow the inbound access in the Network Security Groups from the IP address 168.63.129.16 to
                        communicate with the Google Cloud Service. This IP belongs to Microsoft and acts as DHCP server,
                        DNS server and monitors the host node hosting the Google Cloud Virtual Machine.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ol&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Go to the Firewall rules page in the &lt;a
                        href="https://console.cloud.google.com//networking/firewalls/list"&gt;Google Cloud Platform
                        Console&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click Create firewall rule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Enter a Name for the firewall rule. This name must be unique for the project.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Specify the Network where the firewall rule is implemented.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Specify the Priority of the rule. If this rule will not conflict with any other rules,
                        you can leave the priority on the default of 1000. If you want to give it a higher or lower
                        priority than other rules, give it a lower number to have it evaluated earlier or a higher
                        number to have it evaluated later.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Indicate the Direction of traffic to which you want the rule to apply. In your case
                        ingress.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Indicate the Action as Allow.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Specify the Targets of the rule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Select IP ranges if you want the rule to apply to packets from certain source IP
                        ranges only, then specify those ranges in the Source IP ranges field. In your case, the IP
                        traffic is 168.63.129.16.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click Create.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ol&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Google Cloud docs: create firewall rules' url='https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/using-firewalls#creating_firewall_rules' />
          </references>
          <standards />
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Go to the Firewall rules page in the Google Cloud Platform Console.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Review all firewall rules.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check that each firewall rule is configured correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>