<control ref='GOOGLE-VM07' name='Configure the SSH encryption protocol to connect to the VM' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Configure ports 2222 and 8888 to connect to the Virtual Machine with the SSH transport
                        encryption protocol. Remediation: Use the gcloud command-line tool to start a server on a given
                        local port that forwards all traffic to a remote host over an SSH connection.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        First, take a note of the instance and port that are providing the service to which you would
                        like to establish a secure connection. Next, run the following command:&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        gcloud compute ssh example-instance \&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;blockquote&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        --project my-project \&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        --zone us-central1-a \&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        --ssh-flag=&amp;quot;-L&amp;quot; \&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        --ssh-flag=&amp;quot;2222:localhost:8888&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/blockquote&gt;In the above command, the parameters are defined as follows:&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;example-instance is the name of the instance to which you'd like to connect.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;my-project is your Google Cloud Platform project ID.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;us-central1-a is the zone in which your instance is running.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;2222 is the local port you're listening on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;8888 is the remote port you're connecting to.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;With these example settings, if you open http://localhost:2222/ in your browser, the
                        HTTP connection will go over the SSH tunnel you have just created over to your remote host and
                        connect to the specified instance via SSH and then connect to port 8888 on the same machine, but
                        over an encrypted, secure SSH connection. The gcloud command creates and maintains an SSH
                        connection, and this approach only works while the SSH session is active. As soon as you exit
                        the SSH session that gcloud creates, the port forwarded via http://localhost:2222/ will stop
                        working.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Google Cloud: port forwarding over SSL' url='https://cloud.google.com/solutions/connecting-securely?-419#port-forwarding-over-ssh' />
          </references>
          <standards />
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>Check that the encryption channel SSL is enabled and configured for connections to the
                            VM.
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>