<control ref='GOOGLE-VM02' name='Use Network Security Groups to restrict ingress to port 3389' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Use Network Security Groups (NSG) to filter the ingress/egress network traffic to Google Cloud
                        resources. Set the limit inbound access to port 3389 (Remote Desk Protocol) to IP addresses that
                        require this access in order to avoid undue exposure to risk.

                        Remediation:
                        1. Go to the Firewall rules page in the Google Cloud Platform Console.
                        (https://console.cloud.google.com//networking/firewalls/list)
                        2. Click Create firewall rule.
                        3. Enter a Name for the firewall rule. This name must be unique for the project.
                        4. Specify the Network where the firewall rule is implemented.
                        5. Specify the Priority of the rule. If this rule will not conflict with any other rules, you
                        can leave the priority on the default of 1000. If you want to give it a higher or lower priority
                        than other rules, give it a lower number to have it evaluated earlier or a higher number to have
                        it evaluated later.
                        6. Indicate the Direction of traffic to which you want the rule to apply. In your case ingress.
                        7. Indicate the Action as Allow.
                        8. Specify the Targets of the rule.
                        9. Select the IP ranges you want the "allow" rule to apply to from certain source IP ranges
                        only, then specify those ranges in the Source IP ranges field.
                        10. Specify which Protocols and ports the rule should apply to. In your case, port 3389
                        11. Click Create.
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='Google Cloud docs: create firewall rules' url='https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/using-firewalls#creating_firewall_rules' />
          </references>
          <standards />
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Go to the Firewall rules page in the Google Cloud Platform Console.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check that the corresponding Firewall rule is configured and implemented.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check that inbound traffic though to port 3389 is restricted.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2016-08-02T10:21:32.718'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>