<control ref='Hydras-AWS-EC2-6.3' name='Apply IAM roles for EC2 instances IAM roles for EC2 instances' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>Applications that run on an Amazon EC2 instance need credentials in order to access other AWS
                        services. To provide credentials to the application in a secure way, use IAM roles. A role is an
                        entity that has its own set of permissions, but that isn't a user or group. Roles also don't
                        have their own permanent set of credentials the way IAM users do. In the case of Amazon EC2, IAM
                        dynamically provides temporary credentials to the EC2 instance, and these credentials are
                        automatically rotated for you.
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;When you launch an EC2 instance, you can specify a role for the instance as a launch
                        parameter. Applications that run on the EC2 instance can use the role's credentials when they
                        access AWS resources. The role's permissions determine what the application is allowed to do. It
                        is recommended that all EC2 instances be launched with a role, even if the role has no
                        permissions (as they can be added later if desired).
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;ol&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Login to the AWS Management Console.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Select EC2 from the services menu.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Select &amp;quot;Launch Instance&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Complete the wizard until step 3 at which point ensure an IAM role is selected for the
                        &amp;quot;IAM role&amp;quot; option (note the role must already exist).&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Complete the wizard to launch the instance.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ol&gt;NB: You cannot add a role to an instance that has been launched without one. In these
                        cases create an AMI from an existing instance and launch a new instance, assigning an IAM role
                        as detailed above.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;Content provided by
                        &lt;a href="https://hydrasit.com" target="_blank"&gt; Hydras IT LTD&lt;/a&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references />
          <standards>
            <standard ref='1.19' supportedStandardRef='CIS AWS Standard' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Login to the AWS Management Console.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Select EC2 from the services menu.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Select &amp;quot;Instances&amp;quot; from the left hand menu.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;For each instance in the list:&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;select the instance&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;in the preview pane confirm the instance has an &amp;quot;IAM Role&amp;quot;
                            assigned (if a hyphen &amp;quot;-&amp;quot; is shown then your instance has no role
                            assigned).&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2019-04-01T07:51:15.000'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>