<control ref='AZ-Q04' name='Enable SQL Database auditing' platform='' cost='0' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Enable Azure SQL Database Auditing to audit the database events into the audit log in your Azure
                        Storage account. Auditing can help you maintain regulatory compliance, understand database
                        activity, and gain insight into discrepancies and anomalies that could indicate potential
                        security violations.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ol&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Select SQL databases from the left-hand menu, and click your database on the SQL
                        databases page.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the Settings blade, select Auditing &amp;amp; Threat Detection.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In the database auditing configuration blade, you can check the Inherit settings from
                        server checkbox to designate that this database will be audited according to its server's
                        settings. If this option is checked, you will see a View server auditing settings link that
                        allows you to view or modify the server auditing settings from this context.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;If you prefer to enable an Audit type (or location?) different from the one specified
                        at the server level, uncheck the Inherit Auditing settings from server option, turn ON Auditing,
                        and choose the Blob Auditing Type.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Select Storage Details to open the Audit Logs Storage Blade. Select the Azure storage
                        account where logs will be saved, and the retention period, after which the old logs will be
                        deleted, then click OK at the bottom. Tip: Use the same storage account for all audited
                        databases to get the most out of the auditing reports templates.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;If you want to customize the audited events, you can do this via PowerShell or REST
                        API - see the Automation (PowerShell / REST API) section for more details.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click Save.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ol&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='MS Azure - Get started with SQL database auditing' url='https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/sql-database/sql-database-auditing' />
          </references>
          <standards />
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Select SQL databases from the left-hand menu, and click your database on the SQL
                            databases page.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;In the Settings blade, select Auditing &amp;amp; Threat Detection.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check that the Database Auditing is enabled and correct configured.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2017-06-12T10:15:07.584'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>