<control ref='AZ-Q01' name='Restrict network access to the database' platform='' cost='0' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Set up the firewall rules for the SQL databases in Azure. By default, all connections to the
                        server and the databases inside the server are rejected except for connections from other Azure
                        services. Set the secure configuration 'Allow access to Azure services' to OFF. To connect to
                        the database from an Azure VM or cloud service, create a Reserved IP and allow only the reserved
                        IP address access through the firewall.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;b&gt;Remediation:&lt;/b&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ol&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Log in to the Azure portal.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click SQL databases from the left-hand menu and click the database you would like to
                        configure the firewall rule for on the SQL databases page. The overview page for your database
                        opens, showing you the fully qualified server name (such as
                        mynewserver-20170313.database.windows.net) and provides options for further configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click Set server firewall on the toolbar as shown in the previous image. The Firewall
                        settings page for the SQL Database server opens.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click Add client IP on the toolbar to add the public IP address of the computer
                        connected to the portal with or enter the firewall rule manually and then click Save.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Click OK and then click the X to close the Firewall settings page.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ol&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='MS Azure - Azure SQL Database server-level and database-level firewall rules' url='https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/sql-database/sql-database-firewall-configure' />
          </references>
          <standards />
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Log in to the Azure portal.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Click SQL databases from the left-hand menu and click the database you would like
                            to configure the firewall rule for on the SQL databases page. The overview page for your
                            database opens, showing you the fully qualified server name (such as
                            mynewserver-20170313.database.windows.net) and provides options for further configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Click Set server firewall on the toolbar as shown in the previous image.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check that the firewall for the Database SQL is correctly configured.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        </steps>
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2017-06-12T10:18:20.292'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>