<control ref="IOT2.4.5.5" name="Any product's port(s) that are not required for normal operation should be restricted or disabled" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;If the product has any virtual port(s) that are not required for normal operation, they are only allowed to communicate with authorized and authenticated entities or securely disabled when shipped.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; Where a port is used for field diagnostics, the port input commands are deactivated and the output provides no information which could compromise the device, such as credentials, memory address or function names. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Rationale:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; One of the most important principles in information security is to reduce the attack surface. Open ports are not always a security risk, for example a web server has to have 80 or 443 open otherwise users can not connect to use the web server. Thus taking into account that every open port increases the attack surface, any product's port(s) that are not required for normal operation should be restricted or disabled.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Remediation:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Restrict or disable any port(s) that are not required for normal operation.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; Deactivate port input for port(s) that are used for field diagnostics and ensure their output provides no information which could compromise the device.&lt;/p&gt;</desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references>
                        <reference name="Developer IoT Security Guidance" url="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/IoT_Security_Guidance#Developer_IoT_Security_Guidance"/>
                        <reference name="Top 10 2014-I3 Insecure Network Services" url="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10_2014-I3_Insecure_Network_Services"/>
                    </references>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="2.4.5.5" supportedStandardRef="iotsf-class-2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;Checking for Insecure Network Services includes:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ol&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Determining if insecure network services exist by reviewing your device for open ports using a port scanner.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;As open ports are identified, each can be tested using any number of automated tools that look for DoS vulnerabilities, vulnerabilities related to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UDP&lt;/span&gt; services and vulnerabilities related to buffer overflow and fuzzing attacks.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Reviewing network ports to ensure they are absolutely necessary and if there are any ports being exposed to the internet using UPnP.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ol&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2019-03-13T16:00:44">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>