<control ref="IOT2.4.5.24" name="The software has been designed to fail safely" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;The software has been designed to meet the safety requirements identified in the risk assessment, i.e. in the case of unexpected invalid inputs, or erroneous software operation, the product does not become dangerous, or compromise the security of other connected systems.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Rationale:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; A fail safe software is expected to fail, but when it does it will be in a safe way and security controls and settings remain in effect. The confidentiality and integrity of a system should remain even though availability has been lost. Attackers must not be permitted to gain access rights to privileged objects during a failure that are normally inaccessible. Upon failing, a system that reveals sensitive information about the failure to potential attackers could supply additional knowledge for creating an attack.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Remediation:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Ensure that software has been designed to fail safely. This typically involves several things:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Secure defaults (default is to deny access).&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;On failure undo changes and restore to a secure state.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Always check return values for failure.&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;In conditional code/filters make sure that there is a default case that does the right thing&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references>
                        <reference name="US-CERT: Failing Securely" url="https://www.us-cert.gov/bsi/articles/knowledge/principles/failing-securely"/>
                    </references>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="2.4.5.24" supportedStandardRef="iotsf-class-2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps></steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2019-03-13T16:00:44">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>