<control ref="CSD-SESS-REAUTH" name="Require additional authentication for sensitive operations / high value transactions" platform="" cost="2" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Having gained access to an account, for example through session hijack or cross-site scripting,
                        an attack can compromise data and functionality accessible to the victim. This may include
                        elevated privilege or sensitive data and functionality, such as changing passwords, creating
                        accounts, or transferring funds.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        These functions and data should be further protected from attack using a risk-based
                        authentication model requiring re-authentication, multi-factor authentication, or use of a token
                        to sign transactions or operations.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Implement re-authentication on key functions (such as requiring the old password
                        before setting a new one).&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Use secondary authentication such as a transaction PIN to allow financial transfers.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Critical administrative functionality should require multi-factor authentication (such
                        as a hard or soft token).&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Consider use of signing technologies or tokens that enable the server-side to verify
                        the authenticity of a request and mitigate Man in the Middle (MiTM) or Man in the Browser (MiTB)
                        attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;br /&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="IA-1" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="2.26" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-1"/>
                        <standard ref="2.26" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="2.26" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="A2:2017-Broken Authentication" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Identify critical functionalities of the application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check the risk appetite for those functionalities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Validate that re-authentication is required for those functions if deemed
                            necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-11-24T12:47:31.761000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>