<control ref="RE-AUTH" name="Require re-authentication for critical operations" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Unattended, hijacked, or otherwise compromised user sessions can be leveraged through certain
                        functionality by an attacker to gain more persistent access. For example, they could change the
                        user's password, create a new account within the application, or abuse the privilege of the
                        compromised user to cause damage (an administrative used could potentially modify or destroy
                        data). To mitigate the threat, in addition to controls such as anti-CSRF tokens,
                        re-authentication of key functionality should be implemented.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Requires users verify their identity when performing critical operations. This could
                        be achieved by requiring they re-enter their password, or a secondary secret value. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;In sensitive systems, consider use of multi-factor authentication such as a time based
                        on time password (TOTP), or a signing tokens (c.f. Internet banking solutions using an element
                        of the transaction to be approved as the seed for the OTP).&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.4.1" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="AC-5" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="CM-6" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="IA-10" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="4.13" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-1"/>
                        <standard ref="4.13" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="4.15" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-2"/>
                        <standard ref="4.13" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="4.15" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                        <standard ref="A2:2017-Broken Authentication" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Identify critical functionalities of the application.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Review appropriate controls based on the risk associated with the functions (e.g.
                            which require re-authentication, or token verification).&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Validate the prescribed controls are in place and enforced for the critical
                            functions.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:20.954000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>