<control ref="IOT2.4.6.5" name="Passwords file(s) ownership and access/write permissions are set to Devices' OS's most privileged account" platform="" cost="1" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;If passwords absolutely must be stored in a local file, then passwords file(s) are owned by - and are only accessible to - and writable by the by the Devices' OS's most privileged account.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Rationale:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The Devices' OS's most privileged account or "superuser" is a special user account used for system administration, capable of making unrestricted, potentially adverse, system-wide changes. For that reason it is often recommended that no-one use "superuser" as their normal user account.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;According to the principle of least privilege, most users and applications run under an ordinary account to perform their work, and must be able to access only the information and resources that are necessary for their legitimate purpose. Thus, if a user only needs to be able to view a particular file, that user should have read-only access to it and should not be able to write to that file. Therefore all files that contain critical or sensitive data like the passwords file(s) should have their ownership and their access/write permissions set to the Devices' OS's most privileged account.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Remediation:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Set ownership and access/write permissions for passwords file(s) to Devices' OS's most privileged account.&lt;/p&gt;</desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references>
                        <reference name="The principle of least privilege" url="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Least_privilege"/>
                    </references>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="2.4.6.5" supportedStandardRef="iotsf-class-1"/>
                        <standard ref="2.4.6.5" supportedStandardRef="iotsf-class-2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps></steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2019-03-13T16:00:44">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>