<threat ref="CAPEC-117" name="An attacker monitors data streams to or from a target in order to gather information" state="Expose" source="MANUAL" owner="" library="">
                            <desc>An attacker monitors data streams to or from a target in order to gather information.
                                This attack may be undertaken in order to gather information to support a later attack,
                                or the data collected may be the end goal of the attack. This attack usually involves
                                sniffing network traffic, but may include observing other types of data streams, such as
                                radio. In most varieties of this attack, the attacker is passive and simply observes
                                regular communication, however in some variants the attacker may attempt to initiate the
                                establishment of a data stream or influence the nature of the data transmitted. However,
                                in all variants of this attack, and distinguishing this attack from other data
                                collection methods, the attacker is not the intended recipient of the data stream.
                                Unlike some other data leakage attacks, the attacker is observing explicit data channels
                                (e.g. network traffic) and reading the content. This differs from attacks that collect
                                more qualitative information, such as communication volume, or other information not
                                explicitly communicated via a data stream.
                            </desc>
                            <riskRating confidentiality="50" integrity="50" availability="100" easeOfExploitation="100"/>
                            <references/>
                            <controls>
                                <control ref="MASVS-2.12" mitigation="100"/>
                            </controls>
                            <weaknesses>
                                <weakness ref="CWE-200">
                                    <controls>
                                        <control ref="MASVS-2.12" mitigation="100"/>
                                    </controls>
                                </weakness>
                            </weaknesses>
                        </threat>