<control ref="CWE-204-USERNAME-TIMING" name="Ensure failed login timings do not reveal account status" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        As with variations in error codes and messages, the timing of responses from the application can
                        be used by an attacker to infer information about user accounts and the system. For example, it
                        may be computationally more expensive to check a valid username against its password in the
                        back-end than to reject a login based on an unknown username. This computational cost may be
                        reflected in the delay between attempting to authenticate, and being rejected, which an attacker
                        may be able to detect and use to enumerate accounts.&amp;nbsp;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;The solution will vary depending on the individual implementation, but in general a
                        random time delay should be introduced if a predictable time difference is detectable between
                        valid and invalid accounts&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;For example, login functions that first perform a database select on the username and
                        then on the password could cause the response time to be consistently different for existent and
                        non-existent usernames. If so, a random time delay should be included in the response to mask
                        this difference&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="9.4.2" supportedStandardRef="ISO/IEC 27002:2013"/>
                        <standard ref="IA-1" supportedStandardRef="NIST 800-53"/>
                        <standard ref="2.28" supportedStandardRef="OWASP-ASVS-Level-3"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Identify the authentication verification routines.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Send a series of partially successful and unsuccessful authentication attempts.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;For each of the two groups calculate the average response time and check there is
                            no significant difference between them that could help username enumeration or credential
                            discovery.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;A time-based attack technique could be used to enumerate the users of a given
                            system, if the application takes different time to respond based on the use of a successful
                            username or an invalid one, this could be used to guess the real usernames based on lists
                            (dictionary attack).
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2015-08-15T17:17:15.128000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>