<control ref="PCI-R3-3.1" name="3.1 - Keep cardholder data storage to a minimum" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;implementing data retention and disposal policies, procedures and processes that
                        include at
                        least the following for all cardholder data (CHD) storage:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Limiting data storage amount and retention time to that which is required for legal,
                        regulatory,
                        and/or business requirements&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Specific retention requirements for cardholder data&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Processes for secure deletion of data when no longer needed&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- A quarterly process for identifying and securely deleting stored cardholder data that
                        exceeds
                        defined retention.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;A formal data retention policy identifies what data needs to be retained, and where
                        that data
                        resides so it can be securely destroyed or deleted as soon as it is no longer needed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;The only cardholder data that may be stored after authorization is the primary account
                        number or
                        PAN (rendered unreadable), expiration date, cardholder name, and service code.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Understanding where cardholder data is located is necessary so it can be properly
                        retained or
                        disposed of when no longer needed. In order to define appropriate retention requirements, an
                        entity first
                        needs to understand their own business needs as well as any legal or regulatory obligations that
                        apply to
                        their industry, and/or that apply to the type of data being retained.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="3.1" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;3.1.a Examine the data retention and disposal policies, procedures and processes
                            to verify
                            they include the following for all cardholder data (CHD) storage: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Limiting data storage amount and retention time to that which is
                            required for legal,
                            regulatory, and/or business requirements. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Specific requirements for retention of cardholder data (for example,
                            cardholder data
                            needs to be held for X period for Y business reasons). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Processes for secure deletion of cardholder data when no longer needed
                            for legal,
                            regulatory, or business reasons. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;A quarterly process for identifying and securely deleting stored
                            cardholder data that
                            exceeds defined retention requirements. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;3.1.b Interview personnel to verify that: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;All locations of stored cardholder data are included in the &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;data
                            retention and disposal processes. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Either a quarterly automatic or manual process is in place to identify
                            and securely
                            delete stored cardholder data. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The quarterly automatic or manual process is performed for all locations
                            of cardholder
                            data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;3.1.c For a sample of system components that store cardholder data: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Examine files and system records to verify that the data stored does not
                            exceed the
                            requirements defined in the data retention policy &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Observe the deletion mechanism to verify data is deleted securely.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T08:20:15.824000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>