<control ref="PCI-PAN-STORED-3.4" name="3.4 Use of one-way hashes, truncation, index tokens or strong cryptography is required to store the PAN " platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;PANs stored in primary storage (databases, or flat files such as text files
                        spreadsheets) as
                        well as non-primary storage (backup, audit logs, exception or troubleshooting logs) must all be
                        protected.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;One-way hash functions based on strong cryptography can be used to render cardholder
                        data
                        unreadable. Hash functions are appropriate when there is no need to retrieve the original number
                        (one-way
                        hashes are irreversible). It is recommended, but not currently a requirement, that an
                        additional, random
                        input value be added to the cardholder data prior to hashing to reduce the feasibility of an
                        attacker
                        comparing the data against (and deriving the PAN from) tables of pre-computed hash values.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;The intent of truncation is to permanently remove a segment of PAN data so that only a
                        portion
                        (generally not to exceed the first six and last four digits) of the PAN is stored.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;An index token is a cryptographic token that replaces the PAN based on a given index
                        for an
                        unpredictable value. A one-time pad is a system in which a randomly generated private key is
                        used only once
                        to encrypt a message that is then decrypted using a matching one-time pad and key.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;The intent of strong cryptography (as defined in the &lt;i&gt;PCI DSS and PA-DSS
                        Glossary of Terms,
                        Abbreviations, and Acronyms&lt;/i&gt;) is that the encryption be based on an industry-tested and
                        accepted
                        algorithm (not a proprietary or &amp;quot;home-grown&amp;quot; algorithm) with strong
                        cryptographic keys.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;By correlating hashed and truncated versions of a given PAN, a malicious individual may
                        easily
                        derive the original PAN value. Controls that prevent the correlation of this data will help
                        ensure that the
                        original PAN remains unreadable.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="3.4" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;Examine documentation about the system used to protect the PAN, including the
                            vendor, type
                            of system/process, and the encryption algorithms (if applicable) to verify that the PAN is
                            rendered
                            unreadable using any of the following methods:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- One-way hashes based on strong cryptography,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- Truncation&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- Index tokens and pads, with the pads being securely stored&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;- Strong cryptography, with associated&amp;nbsp;key-management processes and
                            procedures&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;Examine several tables or files from a sample of data repositories to verify the
                            PAN is rendered
                            unreadable (that is, not stored in plain-text).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;Examine a sample of removable media (for example, back-up tapes) to confirm that
                            the PAN is
                            rendered unreadable.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;Examine a sample of audit logs, including payment application logs, to confirm that
                            PAN is
                            rendered unreadable or is not present in the logs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;if hashed and truncated versions of the same PAN are present in the environment,
                            examine
                            implemented controls to verify that the hashed and truncated versions cannot be correlated
                            to reconstruct
                            the original PAN.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-02T21:49:25.327000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>