<control ref="PCI-3.4.1" name="3.4.1 Apply additional controls if disk encryption is used" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>If disk encryption is used (rather than file- or column-level database encryption), logical
                        access must
                        be managed separately and independently of native operating system authentication and access
                        control
                        mechanisms (for example, by not using local user account databases or general network login
                        credentials).
                        Decryption keys must not be associated with user accounts.
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="3.4.1" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;3.4.1.a If disk encryption is used, inspect the configuration and observe the
                            authentication
                            process to verify that logical access to encrypted file systems is implemented via a
                            mechanism that is
                            separate from the native operating system's authentication mechanism (for example, not
                            using
                            local user
                            account databases or general network login credentials). &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;3.4.1.b Observe processes and interview personnel to verify that cryptographic keys
                            are stored
                            securely (for example, stored on removable media that is adequately protected with strong
                            access
                            controls). &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;3.4.1.c Examine the configurations and observe the processes to verify that
                            cardholder data on
                            removable media is encrypted wherever stored. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;Note: If disk encryption is not used to encrypt removable media, the data stored on
                            this media
                            will need to be rendered unreadable through some other method.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-14T15:52:37.520000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>