<control ref="CWE-541" name="Prevent unauthorised access to source code through the service" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;div&gt;
                        Access to the source-code for the application can aid an attacker in determined bugs or
                        vulnerabilities in the code or logic. For closed-source projects it is therefore important to
                        control and restrict access to the source. Application services may unexpectedly expose code,
                        for example a service providing files to a user could be manipulated to access source code if
                        implemented insecurely.
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;ul&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Ensure that source code is not inadvertently disclosed through misconfiguration or
                        vulnerabilities in the service.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Check that configuration files are not downloadable directly from the service, and
                        cannot be read and viewed through the service itself.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;li&gt;Ensure backups, operating system, and version control artifacts do not expose code.&lt;/li&gt;
                        &lt;/ul&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="A3:2017-Sensitive Data Exposure" supportedStandardRef="owasp-top-10-2017"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;ol&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check that the source code of the application is never returned in case it cannot
                            be interpreted.&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Web Servers have a concept called handlers which manages the source code
                            interpretation before sending it to the client. If those handlers are not properly
                            configured, the plain source code would be sent as a default.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check the handlers are correctly configured to support the types of languages your
                            server uses.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;Check also that the source code is not leaked in case of failure.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ol&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-11-08T12:43:53.588000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>