<control ref="EU-GDPR-CONSENT-MECHANISM" name="Create a consent mechanism" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="admin" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>Implement a consent mechanism which allows data subjects (persons of whom personal data is processed) to give their consent for certain processing activities. This is mainly used for cookies and secondary purposes such as direct marketing, newsletters, ...&lt;br/&gt; 
          &lt;br/&gt;The consent mechanism often consists of a check box. These check boxes are required for every single secondary purpose (not allowed to implement one consent box for all purposes). The consent boxes should: &lt;br /&gt;
              &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;be inactive by default (the data subject should active the box)&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;revocable (the data subject must be able to revoke the consent in a way that is as easy as it was to give consent, this can be done by implementing a platform on which the data subject can actively manage his/her consents) &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Traceable (a consent database is required to track when consent was given and revoked. This must include timestamps) &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;br /&gt;You must involve the DPO and/or legal department to decide on the legitimation that can be used.
          </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references>
                        <reference name="EU GDPR - EU Data Protection" url="http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/reform/files/regulation_oj_en.pdf"/>
                    </references>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="Art.6" supportedStandardRef="EU-GDPR"/>
                        <standard ref="Art.7" supportedStandardRef="EU-GDPR"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;ol&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Verify appropriate user personal data consent mechanisms are in place and are not pre-granted.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Verify users can modify their data consent choices in a manner as easy as giving consent.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Verify the above above user activities have been appropriately logged.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2018-01-18T12:41:32.691000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>