<control ref="EU-GDPR-PRIVACY-NOTICE" name="Integrate a privacy notice within the application" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="admin" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>You must involve the DPO in order to receive a GDPR compliant privacy notice. This notice should at least mention:
          &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(a) the identity and the contact details of the controller and, where applicable, of the controller's representative; 
          &lt;br /&gt;(b) the contact details of the Data Protection Officer, where applicable; 
          &lt;br /&gt;(c) the purposes of the processing for which the personal data are intended as well as the legal basis for the processing; 
          &lt;br /&gt;(d) the categories of personal data concerned;
          &lt;br /&gt;(e) the recipients or categories of recipients of the personal data;
          &lt;br /&gt;(f) where applicable, the fact that the controller intends to transfer personal data to a third country or international organization
          &lt;br /&gt;(g) the period for which the personal data will be stored, or if that is not possible, the criteria used to determine that period; 
          &lt;br /&gt;(h) where the processing is based on the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party; 
          &lt;br /&gt;(i) the existence of the right to request from the controller access to and rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing concerning the data subject and to object to processing as well as the right to data portability; 
          &lt;br /&gt;(j) the existence of the right to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal; 
          &lt;br /&gt;(k) the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority; 
          &lt;br /&gt;(l) from which source the personal data originate, and if applicable, whether it came from publicly accessible sources; 
          &lt;br /&gt;(m) the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling
          &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Integrate privacy notice in application, before data subjects enter or push their personal data.
          &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
          This data should also be provided towards the data subject if the data is not gathered directly from the data subject.
          </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references>
                        <reference name="EU GDPR - EU Data Protection" url="http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/reform/files/regulation_oj_en.pdf"/>
                    </references>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="Art.12" supportedStandardRef="EU-GDPR"/>
                        <standard ref="Art.13" supportedStandardRef="EU-GDPR"/>
                        <standard ref="Art.14" supportedStandardRef="EU-GDPR"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;ol&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Verify users have easy access to privacy notices within the application interface.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Verify privacy notices are presented to the user before they submit their personal data.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Verify privacy notices are in accordance with the requirements of the Data Protection practitioner.&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2018-01-18T14:17:13.546000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>