<control ref="CWE-934" name='2.3 Use  "strong cryptography" and industry-recognized protocols with appropriate key strengths (SSH, HTTPS, ...) ' platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>Ensure all the authentication information sent to the administrative service is strongly encrypted on transit.&amp;nbsp;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="2.3" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.3 Select a sample of system components and verify that non-console administrative
                            access is encrypted by performing the following:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.3.a Observe an administrator log on to each system and examine system
                            configurations to verify that a strong encryption method is invoked before the administrator's password is requested.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.3.b Review services and parameter files on systems to determine that Telnet and
                            other insecure remote-login commands are not available for non-console access. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.3.c Observe an administrator log on to each system to verify that administrator
                            access to any web-based management interfaces is encrypted with strong cryptography. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.3.d Examine vendor documentation and interview personnel to verify that strong
                            cryptography for the technology in use is implemented according to industry best practices and/or vendor recommendations.
                            &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;2.3.e If SSL/early TLS is used, perform testing procedures in Appendix A2:
                            Additional PCI DSS Requirements for Entities using SSL/Early TLS.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-02T10:21:32.718000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>