<control ref="PCI-R6-6.3.2" name="6.3.2 - Review custom code prior to release to production" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Review custom code prior to release to production or customers in order to identify
                        any
                        potential coding vulnerability (using either manual or automated processes) to include at least
                        the
                        following:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Code changes are reviewed by individuals other than the originating code author, and
                        by
                        individuals knowledgeable about code-review techniques and secure coding practices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Code reviews ensure code is developed according to secure coding guidelines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Appropriate corrections are implemented prior to release.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Code-review results are reviewed and approved by management prior to release.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Security vulnerabilities in custom code are commonly exploited by malicious individuals
                        to gain
                        access to a network and compromise cardholder data.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;An individual knowledgeable and experienced in code-review techniques should be
                        involved in the
                        review process. Code reviews should be performed by someone other than the developer of the code
                        to allow
                        for an independent, objective review. Automated tools or processes may also be used in lieu of
                        manual
                        reviews, but keep in mind that it may be difficult or even impossible for an automated tool to
                        identify some
                        coding issues.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Correcting coding errors before the code is deployed into a production environment or
                        released to
                        customers prevents the code exposing the environments to potential exploit. Faulty code is also
                        far more
                        difficult and expensive to address after it has been deployed or released into production
                        environments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Including a formal review and sign-off by management prior to release helps to ensure
                        that code is
                        approved and has been developed in accordance with policies and procedures.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="6.3.2" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;6.3.2.a &lt;/b&gt;Examine written software-development procedures and
                            interview
                            responsible personnel to verify that all custom application code changes must be reviewed
                            (using either
                            manual or automated processes) as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code changes are reviewed by individuals other than the originating code
                            author, and by
                            individuals who are knowledgeable in code-review techniques and secure coding practices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code reviews ensure code is developed according to secure coding
                            guidelines (see PCI
                            DSS Requirement 6.5).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appropriate corrections are implemented prior to release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code-review results are reviewed and approved by management prior to
                            release.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                            &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;6.3.2.b &lt;/b&gt;Select a sample of recent custom application changes and
                            verify that
                            custom application code is reviewed according to 6.3.2.a, above.&lt;/p&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T12:26:05.129000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>