<control ref="PCI-R6-6.5.8" name="6.5.8 - Implement robust server side access control" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Improper access control (such as insecure direct object references, failure to
                        restrict URL
                        access, directory traversal, and failure to restrict user access to functions).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;A direct object reference occurs when a developer exposes a reference to an internal
                        implementation
                        object, such as a file, directory, database record, or key, as a URL or form parameter.
                        Attackers can
                        manipulate those references to access other objects without authorization.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Consistently enforce access control in presentation layer and business logic for all
                        URLs.
                        Frequently, the only way an application protects sensitive functionality is by preventing the
                        display of
                        links or URLs to unauthorized users. Attackers can use this weakness to access and perform
                        unauthorized
                        operations by accessing those URLs directly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;An attacker may be able to enumerate and navigate the directory structure of a website
                        (directory
                        traversal) thus gaining access to unauthorized information as well as gaining further insight
                        into the
                        workings of the site for later exploitation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;If user interfaces permit access to unauthorized functions, this access could result in
                        unauthorized individuals gaining access to privileged credentials or cardholder data. Only
                        authorized users
                        should be permitted to access direct object references to sensitive resources. Limiting access
                        to data
                        resources will help prevent cardholder data from being presented to unauthorized resources.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="6.5.8" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;6.5.8 Examine software-development policies and procedures and interview
                            responsible
                            personnel to verify that improper access control-such as insecure direct object
                            references,
                            failure to
                            restrict URL access, and directory traversal-is addressed by coding technique that
                            includes:
                            &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Proper authentication of users &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sanitizing input &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Not exposing internal object references to users &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;User interfaces that do not permit access to unauthorized functions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T13:36:15.084000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>