<control ref="PCI-R6-6.6" name="6.6 - Periodically assess public-facing web applications" platform="" cost="0" risk="0" state="Recommended" owner="" library="" source="MANUAL">
                    <desc>&lt;p&gt;Public-facing web applications are primary targets for attackers, and poorly coded
                        web
                        applications provide an easy path for attackers to gain access to sensitive data and systems.
                        The
                        requirement for reviewing applications or installing web-application firewalls is intended to
                        reduce the
                        number of compromises on public-facing web applications due to poor coding or application
                        management
                        practices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Manual or automated vulnerability security assessment tools or methods review and/or
                        test the
                        application for vulnerabilities&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Use one of the following methods:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Reviewing public-facing web applications via manual or automated application
                        vulnerability
                        security assessment tools or methods, at least annually and after any changes&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Installing an automated technical solution that detects and prevents web-based
                        attacks (for
                        example, a web-application firewall) in front of public-facing web applications, to continually
                        check all
                        traffic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;- Web-application firewalls filter and block non-essential traffic at the application
                        layer. Used
                        in conjunction with a network-based firewall, a properly configured web-application firewall
                        prevents
                        application-layer attacks if applications are improperly coded or configured. This can be
                        achieved through a
                        combination of technology and process. Process-based solutions must have mechanisms that
                        facilitate timely
                        responses to alerts in order to meet the intent of this requirement, which is to prevent
                        attacks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    </desc>
                    <implementations/>
                    <references/>
                    <standards>
                        <standard ref="6.6" supportedStandardRef="PCI-DSS-v3.2"/>
                    </standards>
                    <udts/>
                    <test expiryDate="" expiryPeriod="0">
                        <steps>&lt;p&gt;6.6 For public-facing web applications, ensure that either one of the following
                            methods is
                            in place as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Examine documented processes, interview personnel, and examine records
                            of application
                            security assessments to verify that public-facing web applications are reviewed-using
                            either
                            manual or
                            automated vulnerability security assessment tools or methods-as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;At least annually &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;After any changes &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;By an organization that specializes in application&amp;nbsp;security&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;That, at a minimum, all vulnerabilities in&amp;nbsp;Requirement
                            6.5 are
                            included in the assessment&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;That all vulnerabilities are corrected &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;That the application is re-evaluated after the&amp;nbsp;corrections.&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Examine the system configuration settings and&amp;nbsp;interview
                            responsible personnel
                            to verify that an automated technical solution that detects and prevents web-based attacks
                            (for example, a
                            web-application firewall) is in place as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;ul&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;Is situated in front of public-facing web applications to
                            detect and
                            prevent web-based attacks. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;Is actively running and up to date as applicable. &lt;/p&gt;
                            &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;Is generating audit logs. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;- &amp;nbsp;Is configured to either block web-based attacks, or&amp;nbsp;generate
                            an
                            alert that is immediately investigated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
                            &lt;/ul&gt;
                        </steps>
                        <notes></notes>
                        <references/>
                        <source filename="" args="" type="Manual" result="Not Tested" enabled="true" timestamp="2016-08-05T13:44:25.601000">
                            <output></output>
                        </source>
                        <udts/>
                    </test>
                </control>