<control ref='hipaa-doc-05' name='Document and implement procedures and policies' platform='' cost='1' risk='0' state='Recommended' owner='' library='' source='MANUAL'>
          <desc>	&lt;p&gt;Implement reasonable and appropriate policies and procedures to comply with the standards, implementation specifications, or other requirements of this subpart. This standard is not to be construed to permit or excuse and action that violates any other standard, implementation specification, or other requirements of this subpart. A covered entity may change its policies and procedures at any time, provided that the changes are documented and are implemented in accordance with this subpart.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;	While this standard requires covered entities to implement policies and procedures, the Security Rule does not define either policy or procedure. Generally, policies define an organization&amp;#8217;s approach. For example, most business policies establish measurable objectives and expectations for the workforce, assign responsibility for decision-making, and define enforcement and consequences for violations. Procedures describe how the organization carries out that approach, setting forth explicit, step-by-step instructions that implement the organization&amp;#8217;s policies.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;	Policies and procedures should reflect the mission and culture of the organization; thus, the security rule enables each covered entity to use current standard business practices for policy development and implementation. Policies and procedures required by the security Rule may be modified as necessary to meet the changing needs of the organization, as long as the changes are documented and implemented in accordance with the Security Rule.&lt;/p&gt;</desc>
          <implementations />
          <references>
            <reference name='HIPAA Security Standards: Organizational, Policies and Procedures and Documentation Requirements' url='https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/ocr/privacy/hipaa/administrative/securityrule/pprequirements.pdf' />
          </references>
          <standards>
            <standard ref='164.316(a)' supportedStandardRef='hipaa-required' />
          </standards>
          <udts />
          <test expiryDate='' expiryPeriod='0'>
            <steps />
            <notes />
            <source filename='' args='' type='Manual' result='Not Tested' enabled='true' timestamp='2019-08-09T14:30:48.000'>
              <output></output>
            </source>
            <references />
            <udts />
          </test>
        </control>